<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
 

 

 <channel>
    <title>RFA Home</title>
     <language>en</language>
    <description>
        
            RFA is a private, nonprofit corporation that broadcasts news and information to listeners in Asian countries where full, accurate, and timely news reports are unavailable.
        
    </description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english</link>
    <copyright>Radio Free Asia</copyright>

	 
	 <atom:link href="https://www.rfa.org/english/rss2.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
     

	 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Report: Illegal Logging Still Rampant in Cambodia’s Prey Lang Forest</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/cambodia/illegal-logging-cambodia-01092019153808.html</guid>
        <description>Grassroots environmental group criticizes government efforts to stop tree poachers.</description>
        
	        <author>By Eugene Whong</author>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 20:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/cambodia/cambodia-rosewood-06242016130935.html/cambodia-logging-06242016.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Trucks loaded with timber wait at Cambodian Bavet border post with Vietnam, in file photo. ]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Deforestation in Prey Lang forest in the central plains of Cambodia continues to be a major problem that threatens the local economy, food security and biodiversity, and has the potential to accelerate climate change, according to a recent report by the Prey Lang Community Network (PLCN).</p>
<p>The local grassroots movement to preserve the forest found that the major culprit in deforestation is illegal logging, which has increased in recent years. The group’s 7<sup>th</sup> Monitoring Report, published Monday, also says that the government is making the situation worse by requiring permits to patrol the forest. In addition, roads are causing habitat loss within the forest.</p>
<p>“Illegal logging is still happening at an alarming rate,” the report says.</p>
<p>“Satellite imagery showed a forest loss of 5,600 ha in 2017. This is equivalent to twenty-one football fields of forest disappearing every day.”</p>
<p>Hoeun Sopheap, a Prey Lang activist based in Kampong Thom province, told RFA’s Khmer Service that within the past year, while patrolling the forest, he observed that illegal logging is still rampant and that the loggers have built roads that help them to evade the law. The government is actually making it harder to stamp out illegal logging.</p>
<p>“If we patrol the forest without the cooperation of the Ministry of Environment, they consider it as illegal activity,” He said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, activists from the PLCN criticize the Ministry for failing to resolve a petition they sent regarding a land concession that granted more than 30,000 hectares in Kratie and Stung Treng provinces to Ci Biotech Co ltd.</p>
<p>They asked the Ministry to clarify terms of the concession because it affects protected forest and wildlife sanctuaries.</p>
<p>The activists petitioned the ministry in 2015 and 2016 after the government granted concession to Ci Biotech in 2012 to replant trees on degraded forest areas but there has been no response.</p>
<p>The activists say they have seen saw mill depots in the area and have witnessed loggers exporting timber using the company’s name.</p>
<p>Activist Yim Sopheak said by law, the government can’t grant concessions of more than 10,000 hectares of land, about a third of the concession this particular company received.</p>
<p>Another activist, Ek Vanna, said the company’s activities haven’t benefited the surrounding villages.</p>
<p>“The company doesn’t develop anything, they just cut down the wood,” he said. He added that the company also hasn’t planted any trees.</p>
<p>RFA attempted to contact Ministry Spokesman Neth Paektra for comment on Tuesday but were unable to reach him.</p>
<p>The report recommends removing restrictions on independent patrolling, the closure of logging roads and stopping construction on new roads in the forest, unless absolutely necessary.</p>
<p>PLCN was unsparing in its dim view of government efforts to prevent illegal logging in the report.</p>
<p>“It seems there are no specific measures being taken to address these violations,” the Network wrote.</p>
<p>“Remarkably, every day, many tractors loaded with timber pass unencumbered through forest ranger checkpoints. The timber is not being confiscated and the offenders face no legal consequences for their crimes,” they wrote.</p>
<p>Cambodia has long endured the rampant smuggling of logs and timber—often with the complicity of local authorities—to neighbors such as China and Vietnam, where the wood is used to make high-end furniture.</p>
<p>In May last year, a report by the U.K.-based Environmental Investigation Agency (EIA) said that around 300,000 cubic meters (10,594,400 cubic feet) of timber—including endangered rosewood—had been smuggled out of protected areas in Cambodia to Vietnam with the help of local authorities through some U.S. $13 million paid in bribes between November 2016 and March 2017.</p>
<p>According to the NASA Earth Observatory website, between 2001 and 2014 Cambodia lost a total of 1.44 million hectares (5,560 square miles) of forest—one of the world’s fastest rates of deforestation.</p>
<p><strong><i>Additional reporting by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun.</i></strong></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Abandons Further Democratic Reform as China Tightens Grip</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/reform-01092019124611.html</guid>
        <description>Officials move ahead with plans to criminalize any 'insult' to China's national anthem, without specifying which situations could result in prosecution.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 19:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/reform-01092019124611.html/china-nip2-010919.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Hong Kong official Patrick Nip addresses a press conference in Hong Kong, Jan. 9, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>The Hong Kong government on Wednesday ruled out any further attempt at democratic reform as the government moves ahead with plans to criminalize 'insults' to the national anthem of the People's Republic of China.<br /><br />Patrick Nip, the city's top official in charge of constitutional affairs and liaison with the ruling Chinese Communist Party government in Beijing, said Hong Kong is "in no position" to restart democratic reforms, saying that doing so could be "rash" and lead to "extreme action."<br /><br />Nip, who was responding to a question from pro-democracy lawmaker James To about the likelihood of a democratically elected chief executive for the city in 2022, didn't specify what he meant by "extreme action."<br /><br />He said an Aug. 31, 2014 decree by China's parliament insisting that election candidates be screened by Beijing was a fundamental condition for any reform.<br /><br />"If we are to restart constitutional reform, or further promote its development, this is a starting point," Nip said of the National People's Congress standing committee legal interpretation that sparked the 79-day 2014 Occupy Central civil disobedience movement for fully democratic elections.<br /><br />"If we cannot even reach a consensus on this fundamental legal basis, I don't see how we are in a position to further our reform proposal," he said.<br /><br />His comments came as Hong Kong fell to 73rd place in the Economic Intelligence Unit's (EIU's) annual global democracy index.<br /><br />Last year's banning of the pro-independence Hong Kong National Party (HKNP) and the political screening of election candidates had weakened the city's "already weak democracy," the EIU said.<br /><br /><b>Draft law still vague</b><br /><br />Meanwhile, Nip said the government is going ahead with laws that will ban any act of "altering or insulting" the national anthem, with criminal penalties of up to three years' imprisonment.<br /><br />Police will be given the freedom to bring charges against suspects for up to two years after the alleged offense, Nip said. The usual time limit is six months for minor offenses under Hong Kong law.<br /><br />A draft copy of the bill previously indicated that anyone present in a public place when the "March of the Volunteers" is being played is required to "stand up and show respect."<br /><br />Civic Party lawmaker Jeremy Tam said the current draft is too vague about what exactly constitutes an "insult" to the national anthem.<br /><br />"Let us not forget that this legislation is being proposed by the government," Tam said. "They have a duty to explain the various situations in which such acts might take place, and which acts would and would not be in breach of this law."<br /><br />"And yet, at today's press conference, they refused to give a straight answer to questions about different situations," he said. "The government can't seem to tell us, and yet they want to legislate."<br /><br />Use of the rousing revolutionary tune, which marks the struggle of the ruling Chinese Communist Party to found the People's Republic, will also likely be banned in advertising, at private funerals, or as background music in public venues.<br /><br /><b>National anthem jeered at match</b><br /><br />The move came after Hong Kong football fans jeered, turned their backs, and yelled Cantonese obscenities as the national anthem was played over the loudspeakers at the start of recent soccer matches in the city.<br /><br />Meanwhile, the last British colonial governor of Hong Kong, Chris Patten, said the city had undergone a "general tightening of control" since President Xi Jinping took power in late 2012.<br /><br />"There was a general tightening of control,” Patten told a parliamentary foreign affairs committee in Westminster on Tuesday.<br /><br />"[Hong Kong's autonomy] isn’t just about capitalism, it’s about the rule of law. It’s about free speech, it’s about all the freedoms we associate with pluralism, and I think that’s happened to a considerable extent over the past half a dozen years," he said.<br /><br /><i><b>Reported by Lee Wang-yam for RFA's Cantonese Service, and by Hwang Chun-mei for the Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>More Than 80 Percent of Taiwanese Reject China's 'Unification' Plan</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/more-than-80-percent-of-taiwanese-01092019115150.html</guid>
        <description>President Tsai Ing-wen's insistence that Beijing respect the island's democracy and statehood also wins widespread favor.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/more-than-80-percent-of-taiwanese-01092019115150.html/china-tsai-ing-wen-taiwan-jan5-2019.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Taiwan's President Tsai Ing-wen speaks during a press conference at the Presidential Palace in Taipei, Jan. 5, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p><b>UPDATED at 2:02 P.M. EST on 2018-01-09</b></p>
<p>More than 80 percent of Taiwanese would reject unification with mainland China under the Chinese Communist Party's proposed "one country, two systems" model already in place in Hong Kong and Macau, according to a recent opinion poll.</p>
<p>The results came after Taiwan president Tsai Ing-wen rejected calls from Chinese President Xi Jinping for the democratic island to "unify" with the People's Republic, saying its people have no wish to give up their sovereignty.</p>
<p>In the poll of 1,074 Taiwan residents, more than 61 percent of respondents expressed satisfaction with Tsai's response to Xi, while more than 80 percent said they disapproved of the notion of "one country, two systems" according to Beijing's formulation.</p>
<p>More than 85 percent of respondents supported Tsai's four key conditions for any talks to begin with Beijing: namely, that the People's Republic of China hold formal, state-to-state talks with Taiwan while recognizing its status as a sovereign nation, the Republic of China that fled to the island in 1949 after losing a civil war to the communists on the mainland.</p>
<p>In addition, China would have to "respect Taiwan’s freedom and democracy, deals with the country on peaceful and equal terms, and communicate only on a government-to-government basis," Tsai said.</p>
<p>She said Taiwan "utterly rejects" the idea of "one country, two systems."</p>
<p>Beijing is highly unlikely to agree to such conditions, as it regards the island as a renegade province awaiting "unification," although the Chinese Communist Party has never ruled Taiwan.</p>
<p>The survey by Taiwan's Cross-Straits Policy Association was intended to measure public response to recent statements by Tsai and Xi.</p>
<p>In a Jan. 2 "Letter to our Taiwan compatriots," Xi was insistent that China must be "unified."</p>
<p>"It has been a historical and unavoidable duty of the Chinese Communist Party, Chinese government, and the Chinese people to resolve the matter of Taiwan and unify the motherland ever since 1949," Xi said in the statement.</p>
<p>But he made scant reference to public opinion among the 23 million inhabitants of Taiwan, and said that China would make no promises not to use military force.</p>
<p><b>Veiled threat</b></p>
<p>Many in the region have viewed Xi's "no promises" comment as a veiled threat to Taiwan, and the notion of "one country, two systems" has found little favor even among the opposition nationalist Kuomintang (KMT), which has traditionally sought to improve relations with Beijing.</p>
<p>KMT lawmaker Chiang Wan-an on Tuesday said he was against Xi's proposal for the island, and that he supported Tsai's conditions, known as the "four musts."</p>
<p>“Taiwan is not Hong Kong,” he said, adding that most Taiwanese would not accept unification under the formula.</p>
<p>The "one country, two systems" model was promised to Hong Kong after its 1997 handover to China as an alternative to the direct imposition of Communist Party rule.</p>
<p>However, that city's autonomy has been eroded in recent years by a series of high-profile interventions from Beijing, according to U.S. and U.K. officials, Hong Kong's Bar Association, and international rights groups.</p>
<p>According to Fan Shih-ping of National Taiwan Normal University, Washington is unlikely to want to see Taiwan assimilated into China, either.</p>
<p>"If Taiwan did wind up as part of one country, two systems, that would leave a big hole in U.S. ... strategy for surrounding and containing China in the Pacific," Fan said.</p>
<p>"The U.S. probably sees Tsai Ing-wen and the [ruling] Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) as the most likely to resist this," he said.</p>
<p>Fan added that saber-rattling by Beijing has typically always boosted the DPP, come the next election.</p>
<p>Wang Chih-sheng, secretary-general of the pro-DPP Cross-Strait Policy Association, said the DPP is right to try to build a consensus in Taiwan.</p>
<p>"If the DPP continues with its Taiwan consensus policy ... including cross-party support, the youth and the elderly, then they will be able to build a policy platform that the majority of citizens buy into," Wang said.</p>
<p>"It doesn't matter what they call it; but ... we could make a new consensus to use when Beijing tries to ... force the situation," he said.</p>
<p><b>‘A sacred land’</b></p>
<p>Meanwhile, Taiwan's indigenous people said they have been on the island for 6,000 years, and have no wish to be assimilated into a Chinese nation and treated as "ethnic minorities."</p>
<p>"Taiwan is a sacred land where generations of our ancestors lived, and protected it with their lives," they said in an open letter to President Xi. "It has never belonged to China."</p>
<p>"We have fought against imperialism and every foreign intruder of our land. We have suffered military suppression from colonial and authoritarian regimes," it said. "We have never given up our rightful claim to the sovereignty of Taiwan."</p>
<p>"No government, political party, or organization has the right to negotiate with any foreign power in an attempt to surrender the control of the traditional territory of ours, the indigenous peoples of Taiwan," the letter said.</p>
<p>Tseng Hwa-teh, a member of the Paiwan community, said his people were in favor of self-governance and self-determination.</p>
<p>"It is the fundamental and only idea that will allow different ethnic groups to live in happiness and mutual appreciation and respect on the earth," Tseng said. "It's no longer in keeping with the spirit of the times for us to swallow past oppression."</p>
<p>Officially, Taiwan is still known as the Republic of China, which controls the four islands of Taiwan, Penghu, Kinmen and Matsu.</p>
<p>But Beijing has refused diplomatic ties with any country that also recognizes the Republic of China, and actively encourages Taiwan's partners to switch recognition.</p>
<p>Taiwan was ruled as a Japanese colony in the 50 years prior to the end of World War II, but was handed back to the 1911 Republic of China under the KMT government as part of Tokyo's post-war reparation deal.</p>
<p>The island began a transition to democracy following the death of Chiang's son, President Chiang Ching-kuo, in January 1988, starting with direct elections to the legislature in the early 1990s and culminating in the first direct election of a president, Lee Teng-hui, in 1996.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Hwang Chun-mei for RFA's Mandarin Service, and by Chung Kuang-cheng and Pan Jiaqing for the Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Experts: Kim Jong Un’s Visit to China Sends Dual Message to US</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/korea/kim-visits-china-january-2019-01082019175759.html</guid>
        <description>Second Kim-Trump summit likely, but Kim intends to play ‘China card.’</description>
        
	        <author>By Eugene Whong</author>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/korea/kim-visits-china-january-2019-01082019175759.html/kim-china-2019-jan.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[kim-china-2019-jan]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Kim Jong Un’s fourth visit to China is an indication that North Korea’s leader is preparing for another summit with President Donald Trump, but this week’s visit is also meant to send the message that China and North Korea have strategic ties that Washington cannot ignore, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>According to the state-run Korean Central News Agency (KCNA), Kim’s sojourn in China is to last from Jan. 7-10 and will center on meetings with China’s President Xi Jinping, likely to discuss strategy ahead of negotiations with the United States.</p>
<p>Kim’s first diplomatic foray of 2019, followed a hectic year of Korean peninsula diplomacy last year, with Kim also meeting South Korean President Moon Jae-in three times and holding a high-profile Singapore summit with Trump in June.</p>
<p>Key points expected to be discussed at a proposed second North Korea-U.S. summit are North Korea’s denuclearization, addressed in Singapore in a vaguely worded pledge.</p>
<p>With progress on nuclear issues stalled, Kim has started to demand relief from sanctions implemented under U.N. Security Council resolutions in response to Pyongyang’s repeated nuclear and ballistic missile tests over the past decade.</p>
<p>Experts say that this visit also underscores that China has a major role to play in U.S. negotiations with North Korea and that Chinese involvement in North Korean issues could be used by Beijing as a bargaining chip in tense trade negotiations between the U.S. and China.</p>
<p>“This is another example of Kim Jong Un taking advantage of the situation in Washington and going to China not only to get permission from Xi Jinping but to send an underlying message to Washington, to Trump being that hey, you’re not the only game in town. I have this big China card. So I think there is a dual message there,” said Joseph Yun, Senior Adviser to the Asia Program at the US Institute for Peace.</p>
<p>“Essentially this is pretty much the repeat of last year, when he went to China to get the green light from Xi Jinping that it is okay to have another summit, with Trump,” said Yun, a retired U.S. diplomat who was speaking on a panel in Washington on Northeast Asia strategy in 2019.</p>
<p>“I do think that a second summit will be arranged quite soon, probably at the end of February or early March,” he added.</p>
<p>Former U.S. ambassador to South Korea Kathleen Stephens told the same panel that the Kim-Xi meeting showed the importance of the U.S. working closely with other governments in dealing with North Korean issues.</p>
<p>“We need to deepen the process of consultations with Seoul and also with others in the region,” said Stephens, president and CEO of the Washington-based Korea Economic Institute of America.</p>
<p>“Kim Jong Un going to China is a reminder, and probably a very explicit one, that China has both equity and influence in this,” she said.</p>
<p>Former Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Christopher Hill told RFA’s Korean Service that this week’s meetings in Beijing are “part of the process of warming between North Korea and China.”</p>
<p>“China is not happy with the way the U.S. has pursued [the nuclear] issue. The U.S. has gone on the bilateral track and ignored other players in the region, especially China,” said Hill.</p>
<p>Hill expressed concern that the Chinese may be pressing on Kim their view that the U.S. should remove its 28,000 troops from South Korea as part of any settlement and they may attempt to encourage him to stick to that point in negotiations with Trump.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Bruce Bennett, a researcher for the RAND Corporation, said of the meeting, “Kim has been clearly preparing for his second summit meeting with President Trump.”</p>
<p>“I think that Kim is worried that the President will tell him ‘enough is enough’. It’s time for Kim to stop stalling on denuclearization,” he said.</p>
<p>“Kim wants China’s support. Kim also wants China to relax economic sanctions against North Korea, because China is North Korea’s major trading partner. Any action it takes to relax sanctions could make a major difference for North Korea,” said Bennett.</p>
<p><b>Across the pond</b></p>
<p>Experts in South Korea seemed to agree with the assessments of their U.S. counterparts.</p>
<p>Professor Shin Sangjin of Kwangwoon University said, “Kim’s visit to China indicates that another U.S.-North Korea summit will happen soon, especially since President Trump has been saying possible locations are being discussed.”</p>
<p>“Kim wants to maximize his leverage in negotiations with the U.S. Also I think that North Korea is aiming to deliver a clear message that China strongly remains its cooperative ally in the region,” said Shin.</p>
<p>Cho Han-Bum of the Korea Institute for National Unification said that the visit is in line with themes discussed by Kim during his New Year’s address, in which he warned that Pyongyang may change its approach to nuclear talks if Washington persists with sanctions.</p>
<p>“[He] indicated multilateral agreements should be pursued to build a permanent peace regime, clearly implying the role of China,” Cho said.</p>
<p>“North Korea is [through the visit] boasting its improved ties with China.”</p>
<p><strong><i>Additional Reporting by Sangmin Lee and Yong Jae Mok for RFA’s Korean Service. Translated by Yewon Ji.</i></strong></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Myanmar Holds Talks With China to Reopen Border Crossing in Northern Shan State</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmar-holds-talks-with-china-to-reopen-border-crossing-01082019165648.html</guid>
        <description>Fruit dealers rely on the Muse-Ruili passage to export their produce to China’s Yunnan province.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/chinese-authorities-arrest-myanmar-nationals-11282018165055.html/myanmar-border-crossing-china-undatd-photo.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Vehicles and motorbikes line up in Myanmar to pass through a border crossing to China in an undated photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Myanmar’s deputy commerce minister met China’s ambassador to the country on Monday in Naypyidaw to discuss the reopening of the busy border crossing at Muse in northern Shan state for trucks carrying Myanmar produce and seafood, whose closure in December caused hardship for traders.</p>
<p>Deputy Commerce Minister Aung Htoo and a delegation from the Chinese embassy on Monday agreed to extend operating hours at the alternative Kyukok-Pansai border crossing and to add two additional lanes there to let trucks pass while the Kyin San Kyawt passage north of Muse township remains closed.</p>
<p>Minister of Commerce Than Myint, who also attended the meeting, said officially designating Kyin San Kyawt as a regular border gate would relieve traffic congestion between the countries during the watermelon and muskmelon season, Myanmar News Agency reported.</p>
<p>The Kyin San Kyawt crossing is used only to transport fruit and seafood export from Myanmar into China.</p>
<p>When Myanmar soldiers first shut down the crossing on Dec. 27 but gave no reason for the closure, more than 1,000 Myanmar trucks carrying mainly watermelon to China eventually became stranded, causing huge financial losses for farmers and fruit dealers, those involved in the business said.</p>
<p>But some dealers blamed the border closure on Chinese authorities responsible for inspecting the contents of the vehicles, citing a lack of manpower, though it later came to light that their use of advanced security measures such as fingerprinting and facial recognition had caused delays.</p>
<p>It was later disclosed that Myanmar shut down the Kyin San Kyawt checkpoint on its side of the border as a security measure after an armed group attacked a local people’s militia, the official <i>Global New Light of Myanmar</i> reported.</p>
<p>As a result, trucks had to be redirected to the Kyukok-Pansai border crossing — an unofficial passage — where they were allowed to enter the Chinese border town of Wanding in Yunnan province’s Ruili city on Dec. 29, the report said.</p>
<p>During the meeting, Li Xiaoyan, minister counselor from the China embassy to Myanmar, discussed efforts to officially open the Kyin San Kyawt border crossing and plan to decrease traffic congestion by increasing cargo inspection times and assigning more inspectors, Myanmar News Agency reported.</p>
<p>The Chinese side also said it would work with Myanmar to increase the number of border passages between the two countries and to quickly reopen the Kyin San Kyawt crossing gate, the report said.</p>
<p>Naing Win, chairman of the Myanmar Watermelon and Muskmelon Producers and Exporters Association, told RFA’s Myanmar Service that Myanmar’s Ministry of Commerce informed his organization that both sides agreed to increase hours at the Kyukok-Pansai border crossing and add two more lanes at the checkpoint.</p>
<p>RFA called the Yan Naing Htun, the ministry’s permanent secretary, for comment, but was unable to reach him.</p>
<p>Fruit traders meanwhile say more than 1,000 trucks have spent hours lined up in the rain to pass through the Kyukok-Pansai crossing which has only two lanes for people and goods passing in both directions between 6 a.m. and 8:30 p.m.</p>
<p>Only 250 trucks can enter China through the crossing each day, they said.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Thiri Min Zin for RFA’s Myanmar Service. Translated by Khet Mar. Written in English by Roseanne Gerin.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Myanmar’s Arakan Army Denies Link to Muslim Militant Group in Rakhine State</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmars-arakan-army-denies-link-01082019163459.html</guid>
        <description>The ethnic army also objects to a government spokesman’s warning for supporters not to back the organization. </description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmars-arakan-army-denies-link-01082019163459.html/myanmar-wounded-police-aa-atack-rakhine-jan7-2019.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Lieutenant General Aung Win Oo (2nd R), chief of the Myanmar Police Force, visits an injured border policeman in a hospital in 
Buthidaung township, western Myanmar's Rakhine state, Jan. 7, 2019. ]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>The Arakan Army on Tuesday denied that it is allied with a Rohingya Muslim militant group and objected to a Myanmar government spokesman’s warning to its supporters not to back the insurgent organization after it conducted deadly attacks on police outposts in northern Rakhine state last week.</p>
<p>Coordinated assaults by the AA on four police outposts in Buthidaung township on Jan. 4 left 13 policemen dead and injured nine others. The rebel army said it lost three of its soldiers in the violence.</p>
<p>At a news conference on Monday, President’s Office spokesman Zaw Htay accused the AA of having ties to the Arakan Rohingya Salvation Army (ARSA), a Muslim militant group that in August 2017 launched deadly assaults on 30 police outposts and an army base in northern Rakhine state, triggering a brutal military crackdown during which thousands were killed and more than 725,000 Rohingya fled across the border to Bangladesh.</p>
<p>In a statement on its website and Facebook page, the AA said Zaw Htay’s statements were inappropriate, viewing them as an attempt by the government and the military to stir up misunderstanding between the Arakan military group’s allies and ethnic Rakhine support base.</p>
<p>AA commander-in-chief Major General Tun Myat Naing also posted an online message that the AA does not have any connection to ARSA.</p>
<p>The AA, which is fighting the Myanmar military for greater autonomy in Rakhine state, represents the region’s Buddhist Rahkine ethnic group, while ARSA is a militant group that purports to speak for Muslim Rohingyas.</p>
<p>Rakhine ethnics said that it is impossible not to support the AA when all groups in the multiethnic but divided state want equality and the right to self-determination through military and politics means.</p>
<p>They also noted that Rakhine has been the poorest state in Myanmar long before AA attacked the police outposts, thereby negating Zaw Htay’s statement that the region’s development would suffer because of the Rakhine people’s backing of the AA.</p>
<p>Pe Than, a lower house lawmaker from the hard-line Buddhist Arakan National Party (ANP) who represents the Myebon township constituency, said that the Rakhine people did not believe Zaw Htay’s remark that the AA has links to ARSA.</p>
<p>“No Rakhine would accept the AA having ties to the Arakan Rohingya Salvation Army, and it would never happen,” he said.</p>
<p>“If the AA tried to have ties with ARSA, only the AA would face negative consequences,” he said. “We don’t believe these rumors. We want both sides [the government and the AA] to move forward to achieve peace instead of blaming each other.”</p>
<p><b>‘A better way’</b></p>
<p>The AA is one of 11 ethnic armed groups that have not signed the government’s nationwide cease-fire accord of October 2015, an agreement inked by 10 other rebel armies to end decades of civil war in the developing country.</p>
<p>Fighting intensified between the AA and Myanmar Army in December after Arakan troops ambushed a military column conducting “area clearance operations” near the Myanmar-Bangladesh border on Monday, according to an account by the national forces. But the AA attributed the hostilities to an intrusion by the Myanmar military into an AA-controlled area to conduct operations.</p>
<p>Myanmar forces declared a four-month unilateral cease-fire on Dec. 21 in five military regions in a bid to breathe life into the country's teetering peace process by enticing separatist ethnic armies to join talks with the central government. The cease-fire excludes Rakhine state, however.</p>
<p>Ann Thar Gyi, chairman of the local civil society organization Thingaha Kanlat Rakhita Aid Association, said his group will support any organization or individuals if they work for development in Rakhine state.</p>
<p>“The government is talking about development in Rakhine only after having all this fighting in Rakhine,” he said. “It’s like they are saying just what they want to say without thinking about people’s interests.”</p>
<p>Hla Myint, spokesman for the Arakan League for Democracy (ALD), another political party active in Rakhine state, said Zaw Htay’s comments at the press conference would drive people away from the government.</p>
<p>“I believe it would be better to find a better way to resolve the problem,” he said. “Local people in the rural areas have been afraid of both the military as well as of the AA all their lives.”</p>
<p>Kyaukphyu resident Tun Kyi told RFA’s Myanmar Service that he was disappointed with Zaw Htay’s words.</p>
<p>“We have not only the AA as an armed group, but also all other ethnic minorities have their armed groups in the country, and they have been fighting with government army,” he said.</p>
<p>“No ethnic minority will listen to government telling them not to support their armed groups,” he said. “People in Kachin state support the KIA [Kachin Independence Army], and people in Rakhine will support the Rakhine armed group, the AA.”</p>
<p><b>Visit by journalists</b></p>
<p>Meanwhile, a group of journalists on a government-sponsored trip to northern Rakhine on Monday talked to villagers and police officers about the deadly attacks by the AA.</p>
<p>Reporters from RFA, Voice of America, Democratic Voice of Burma, Mizzima and the <i>Myanmar Times </i>arrived in Maungdaw township, adjacent to Buthidaung, by military helicopter along with Lieutenant General Aung Win Oo, chief of the Myanmar Police Force, and Khin Maung Tin, deputy minister of the State Counselor’s Office.</p>
<p>A policeman from the Kahtee Hla police outpost, one of the four stations the AA attacked, told them that their barking dogs alerted police to the approaching insurgents.</p>
<p>“They opened fire with heavy weapons, and we responded with heavy weapons,” he said. “We were engaged in defense for three hours because they had more troops and better weapons. We were very afraid because we never experienced anything like this before.”</p>
<p>Police Sergeant Win Ko from the Kahtee Hla outpost said that some Rakhine villagers were seen with the AA troops during the attack.</p>
<p>“We serve here to protect the Rakhine people, but they helped the AA attack us,” he said, adding that villagers were definitely involved in assaults on the police outpost.</p>
<p>Police Brigadier General Myint Toe, commander of the Border Guard Police Force No. 1, told the reporters that police are now working with the military on ensuring stability in the restive region.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Wai Mar Tun and Min Thein Aung for RFA’s Myanmar Service. Translated by Khet Mar. Written in English by Roseanne Gerin.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Two Cambodia Opposition Officials Barred From Politics to Seek ‘Pardon’ After Amendment Approval</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/cambodia/pardons-01082019154551.html</guid>
        <description>Acting opposition leader Sam Rainsy urges those banned to refrain from falling into a ruling party ‘trap.’</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/cambodia/pardons-01082019154551.html/cambodia-hun-sen-parade-jan-2019.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Prime Minister Hun Sen (L) waves to government civil servants with National Assembly President Heng Samrin during a parade at the Olympic Stadium in Phnom Penh, Jan. 7, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP Photo]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p><b>UPDATED at 1:25 P.M. EST on 2019-01-09</b><br /><br />At least two senior officials from Cambodia’s opposition who were barred from politics said they will seek a “pardon” to have their rights reinstated after King Norodom Sihamoni approved an amendment to the country’s law on political parties on Tuesday.<br /><br />Kong Koam, the former president of the opposition Sam Rainsy Party (SRP), and his son Kong Bora, a former senior official with the main opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP), said they will ask for individual “pardons” on Wednesday to resume political activities, according to a condition Prime Minister Hun Sen has said must be met before they can take advantage of the new amendment to overturn their ban.<br /><br />“The reason I will request to be pardoned is because I can’t stay an outlaw,” Kong Bora told RFA’s Khmer Service, adding that he had never violated any law. His father, whose SRP merged with the Human Rights Party (HRP) to form the CNRP ahead of Cambodia’s 2013 ballot, could not be reached for comment.<br /><br />The two were among 118 officials slapped with a five-year suspension of political rights as part of a decision by the Supreme Court in November 2017 to dissolve the CNRP for its role in an alleged plot to topple the government.<br /><br />Prime Minister Hun Sen’s ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) effectively ran uncontested in Cambodia’s July 29 general election and won all 125 seats in parliament, drawing condemnation from Western nations who called the ballot unfree and unfair amid the crackdown on the opposition and other rollbacks on democracy.<br /><br />In late December, Hun Sen’s Constitutional Council unanimously approved an amendment to the draft law on political parties proposed by the one-party parliament, paving the way for the reinstatement of political rights to the 118 CNRP officials, in what was widely seen as a bid to ease international pressure on his government.<br /><br />On Tuesday, the king signed off on the legislation, which does not provide for the reestablishment of the CNRP, and which Hun Sen has said will only allow the opposition officials to return to politics if they each make an individual request for a “pardon.”<br /><br />Critics have called it a “trap” aimed at fracturing the CNRP.<br /><br /><b>Call to ‘remain strong’</b><br /><br />Meanwhile, CNRP acting president Sam Rainsy, who is living in self-imposed exile to avoid a string of convictions issued by courts seen as beholden to Hun Sen, urged the 118 senior CNRP officials to reject the prime minister’s demand that they request pardons, calling it “a trick” in a post to his Facebook page.<br /><br />“I call on the 118 CNRP officials to remain strong, not to fall into Hun Sen's trap, and not to unknowingly serve the current dictatorship,” he wrote.<br /><br />“Please follow the example of [other CNRP members] who have been released from jail and vowed to continue our righteous fight for freedom and democracy.”<br /><br />Sam Rainsy said that the officials should wait until Hun Sen agrees to reinstate the CNRP, release the party’s president Kem Sokha—who is under house arrest facing charges of treason—and call for a new election that includes all parties.<br /><br />CPP spokesman Sok Ey San said Tuesday that with the amendment to the law on political parties approved, his party is waiting for former CNRP officials with open arms.<br /><br />“The door has been opened—all we are waiting for is people to come,” he said.<br /><br />Hun Sen has regularly called on CNRP officials to defect since their party was dissolved and recently suggested that increasing the number of local level government positions in Cambodia would entice formerly elected opposition members to return to politics with the CPP.<br /><br />Last week, parliament approved draft laws to increase the number of positions, but observers have said the current amount is sufficient, and that existing councilors should instead be made more effective through better training and increased budgets.<br /><br /><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.<br /><br />CORRECTION: An earlier version of this report incorrectly referred to Kong Koam as a former senior CNRP official.<br /></b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>China Jails Three Activists For Video 'Mocking' President Xi Jinping</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/xijinping-insult-01082019134837.html</guid>
        <description>A social media clip made by the activists was judged to have 'insulted' a Chinese leader, leading to 20-month jail terms.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 19:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/xijinping-insult-01082019134837.html/activists-insult.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Supporters of Civil Rights and Livelihood Watch website editor Ding Lingjie gather outside a courthouse  in Beijing, Dec. 28, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ren Quanniu]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Authorities in the Chinese capital have sentenced citizen journalist</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Ding Lingjie and two petitioners to jail for making a video 'mocking'</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> President Xi Jinping during a holiday season crackdown on dissent.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Ding was tried alongside petitioners Li Xuehui and Wang Fengxian by</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> the Shijingshan District People's Court in Beijing on Dec. 28, the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Chinese Human Rights Defenders (CHRD) network said in a statement on</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> its website.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">All three were handed 20-month jail terms after being found guilty of</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> "picking quarrels and stirring up trouble," the group, which compiles</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> and translates reports from rights activists inside China, said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Wang's sentence was suspended for two years, and it was unclear if she</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> had any role in the video. However, her elderly mother took part in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> the clip.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">The case against the three hinged on a video clip shot by Li that the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> authorities said had "insulted a national leader" by mocking Xi.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Ding's lawyer Ren Quanniu said his client plans to appeal the jail</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> term, although the vast majority of appeals to higher courts in China</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> result in the upholding of the initial verdict and sentence.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"All three defendants pleaded not guilty ... and also expressed</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> dissatisfaction, as part of their individual defenses, with the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> verdict and sentence," Ren said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">He said there had been a strong police presence outside the court</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> buildings during the sentencing hearing.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"The Beijing authorities dispatched large numbers of police, because</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> there were a lot of people they regard as so-called '[politically]</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> sensitive individuals' being watched," Ren said. "There were a lot of</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> police vehicles and officers outside the court buildings; they took</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> this very seriously."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"Some of [the activists] were taken away from the area around the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> court building by the state security police," he said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><b><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">'<span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Hostile foreign forces'</span></span></b></p>
<p><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "></span>Ding, who is being held at the Shijingshan Detention Center in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Beijing, had been working as an editor of the Civil Rights and</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Livelihood Watch website at the time of her disappearance in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Shandong's Zibo city in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3638_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3644_com_zimbra_date">September 2017</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Police refused to allow her lawyer to meet with her until after she</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> had been formally arrested in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3639_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3645_com_zimbra_date">November 2017</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">, CHRD said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Liu Feiyue, 48, who founded Civil Rights and Livelihood Watch, stood</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> trial at Hubei's Suizhou Intermediate People's Court in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3640_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3646_com_zimbra_date">August 2018</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">on</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> charges of "incitement to subvert state power."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Xi has repeatedly warned against "hostile foreign forces" attempting</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> to overthrow the ruling Chinese Communist Party by infiltrating China</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> with "Western" religious practices and ideas like democracy,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> constitutional government, and human rights.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Liu was among more than 300 lawyers, law firm staff, rights activists,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> and relatives who were detained, questioned, or placed under</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> surveillance or other restrictions in a nationwide police operation</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> targeting the legal profession and related activists launched in July</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> 2015.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Shandong activist Wang Jiangfeng, who was himself jailed for two years</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> for referring to the president as "Steamed Bun Xi," said the Communist</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Party is terrified of the speed with which video clips can go viral.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"They are really afraid of losing power, because a lot of people in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> China can see all too clearly, and they want democracy," Wang said.</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> "The Chinese Communist Party fears it would lose its power and</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> privilege if that happened."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"That's why they use these methods to suppress people."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Wang was sentenced by the Zhaoyuan People's Court after being found</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> guilty of "picking quarrels and stirring up trouble."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">He was accused of referring to the head of the ruling Chinese</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Communist Party as "Steamed Bun Xi" in a group message to the social</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> media platforms WeChat and QQ. His defense attorney Zhu Shengwu was</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> later stripped of his license to practice.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"Steamed Bun Xi" has been a banned phrase on China's tightly</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> controlled internet since the president ordered the buns during a</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> visit to a Beijing restaurant in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3641_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3647_com_zimbra_date">December 2013</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">, prompting petitioners</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> to gather outside toting a placard that read "President Xi, I'd like</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> to eat steamed buns too" in a bid to get their grievances against the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> government heard.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">The incident sparked an online meme in which Xi was referred to</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> jokingly as Steamed Bun Xi, in a pun on the name of a legendary Song</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> dynasty official who fought corruption. Censors later banned the meme,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> deleting social media posts that contained references to it.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><i><b><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Reported by Wong Lok-to for RFA's Cantonese Service. Translated and</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> edited by Luisetta Mudie.</span></b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Toddler Son of Uyghur Political ‘Re-Education Camp’ Detainees Drowns in Frozen Ditch</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/drowning-01082019130159.html</guid>
        <description>Rahmutullah Shirbaqi had been living with his elderly grandparents when he went missing last month.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 18:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/children-10182017144425.html/uyghur-children-and-police-april-2017-1000.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[A Uyghur woman carries a toddler as children play near a cage protecting Chinese paramilitary policemen on duty in Urumqi, in a file photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP Photo]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>The two-year-old son of an ethnic Uyghur couple detained in a political “re-education camp” in northwest China’s Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region (XUAR) has drowned after falling through ice into an irrigation ditch in Hotan (in Chinese, Hetian) prefecture, according to local officials.<br /><br />Sources recently told RFA’s Uyghur Service that Rahmutullah Shirbaqi disappeared from his home in Qaraqash (Moyu) county’s Zawa township on Dec. 21, while in the care of his grandfather, 78-year-old Matnury Mahsut, and grandmother, 68-year-old Mahtumhan Tursunniyaz.<br /><br />Shirbaqi’s body was found three days later and authorities determined that he had drowned after plunging through ice covering a ditch in front of his house in Chokanjilgha village, where his grandparents had raised him since his parents were sent to the Bostankol Re-education Camp in the county seat a year earlier.<br /><br />An officer at the Hotan prefecture police headquarters told RFA that she was not authorized to discuss Shirbaqi’s case, while two officials from the prefectural government said they had heard a two-year-old boy had died, but were unsure of other details.<br /><br />However, a resident of a neighboring village in Qaraqash told RFA on condition of anonymity that his local ruling Communist Party secretary had recently cautioned villagers to be extra vigilant with their children because of a drowning in the area.<br /><br />“He said we need to take good care of our kids at home because a boy died falling into a ditch,” the resident explained, adding that village officials said the boy’s parents had been detained in a re-education camp, where authorities have detained Uyghurs and other Muslim ethnic minorities accused of harboring “strong religious views” and “politically incorrect” ideas throughout the XUAR since April 2017.<br /><br />While seeking additional information about Shirbaqi’s death, RFA contacted an officer from the Qaraqash county police department, who said the boy has a sister who is a junior at Zawa township’s No. 2 Middle School.<br /><br />“She told the school when her brother disappeared,” the officer said.<br /><br />“Her supervising teacher told me that the boy was found dead. The first thing that came to my mind was, ‘what were the parents doing when he disappeared,’ but then I learned that they weren’t living with him and he was in the care of his grandparents.”<br /><br />The officer said the weather had been quite cold in Hotan in recent weeks and that ice had formed on top of area irrigation ditches around the time Shirbaqi drowned.<br /><br />He said he was unsure whether Shirbaqi’s parents had been sentenced to prison or if they were being held at a re-education camp—only that they “weren’t at home” when the boy went missing.<br /><br />But officials from Chokanjilgha village confirmed Shirbaqi’s parents had been detained at the Bostankol Re-education Camp, with one local police officer saying they were sent to the facility around one year earlier for “a phone issue,” without providing further details.<br /><br />An official from the village government told RFA she had taken Shirbaqi along with his grandparents to the camp multiple times, “but they never got a chance to meet with the boy’s parents.”<br /><br />“The grandparents have pled to meet with the parents, saying their health is poor … but the police guarding the camp won’t let them in,” she said.<br /><br />“We had stamps of approval from the prefectural police department, the county judicial department, the county Public Security Bureau, and the neighborhood committee to visit them. We went to see them 20 times in a two-month period, but were always turned back.”<br /><br />Shirbaqi accompanied his grandparents during their last attempt to visit his parents on Dec. 18, the village official said, just days before he went missing.<br /><br />She said it was unclear whether his parents are aware of his death.<br /><br /><b>Camp network</b><br /><br />While Beijing initially denied the existence of re-education camps, chairman of the XUAR, Shohrat Zakir, told China’s official Xinhua news agency in October that the facilities are an effective tool to protect the country from terrorism and provide vocational training for Uyghurs.<br /><br />Reporting by RFA’s Uyghur Service and other media organizations, however, has shown that those in the camps are detained against their will and subjected to political indoctrination, routinely face rough treatment at the hands of their overseers, and endure poor diets and unhygienic conditions in the often overcrowded facilities.<br /><br />Adrian Zenz, a lecturer in social research methods at the Germany-based European School of Culture and Theology, has said that some 1.1 million people are or have been detained in the camps — equating to 10 to 11 percent of the adult Muslim population of the XUAR.<br /><br />In November 2018, Scott Busby, the deputy assistant secretary in the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights and Labor at the U.S. Department of State, said there are "at least 800,000 and possibly up to a couple of million" Uyghurs and others detained at re-education camps in the XUAR without charges, citing U.S. intelligence assessments.<br /><br />Citing credible reports, U.S. lawmakers Marco Rubio and Chris Smith, who head the bipartisan Congressional-Executive Commission on China, recently called the situation in the XUAR "the largest mass incarceration of a minority population in the world today."<br /><br /><b>Children left behind</b><br /><br />An Oct. 21 report by the official <i>Global Times</i> promoting the camps as “training centers” also included photos of children in Hotan prefecture whose parents had been placed in camps, and claimed that they are warmly cared for at special “schools,” where they engage in educational courses and other activities.<br /><br />But sources have told RFA that Uyghur children whose parents have been sent to camps are regularly sent to orphanages that are seriously overcrowded, calling the conditions “terrible,” with children “locked up like farm animals in a shed.”<br /><br />Others say that while the orphanages received substantial cash donations from the public, “only a very little is spent on the children,” and that the facilities save money by giving the kids meat only once a week, while the rest of the time they are provided with “rice soup.”<br /><br />RFA has received several reports of Uyghur children in the XUAR dying or suffering severe injuries while their parents are detained and they lack adequate care.<br /><br />In August, sources told RFA that a 10-year-old boy from Kashgar (Kashi) prefecture’s Makit (Maigaiti) county, whose parents were being held in a re-education camp, had drowned in the area’s Zerepshan River.<br /><br />In March, sources reported that eight-year-old Esma Ahmet, whose father was being held at a political re-education camp, had suffered burns to nearly 60 percent of her body a month earlier when a stove overturned at her home in Hotan’s Guma (Pishan) county, and was in urgent need of medical treatment.<br /><br /><b><i>Reported by Shohret Hoshur for RFA’s Uyghur Service. Translated by Alim Seytoff. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</i></b></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>China 'Offered to Spy' on Hong Kong-Based Journalists With The Wall Street Journal</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/china-offered-to-spy-on-hong-kong-based-journalists-01082019110823.html</guid>
        <description>Freshly leaked documents indicate that Chinese officials thought nothing of bugging and surveilling the paper's journalists in violation of Hong Kong's promised autonomy.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 16:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/china-offered-to-spy-on-hong-kong-based-journalists-01082019110823.html/china-hkja-fcc-hong-kong-oct8-2018.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Chris Yeung (C), chairperson of the Hong Kong Journalist Association, stands next to Foreign Correspondents' Club 
president Florence de Changy (3rd R) and legislator Claudia Mo (2nd R) as they speak to journalists before handing over petitions to the Hong Kong government calling for an explanation of its rejection of a visa for Financial Times journalist Victor Mallet, in Hong Kong, Oct. 8, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Chinese officials offered to install bugs and surveillance equipment in the homes of foreign journalists in Hong Kong in 2016, as part of a bail-out offer to the Malaysian government's 1MDB fund that is embroiled in a massive corruption scandal, <i>The Wall Street Journal</i> reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Citing minutes from "a series of previously undisclosed meetings," the paper said ruling Chinese Communist Party officials had offered to use Beijing's clout to get third countries to drop their investigations into allegations that officials close to then-Prime Minister Najib Razak had appropriated money from the fund.</p>
<p>The minutes show that the Chinese officials also offered to bug the homes and offices of <i>WSJ</i> reporters writing about the scandal from Hong Kong, in a bid to discover their sources, it said.</p>
<p>Najib has denied any wrongdoing in the 1MDB affair. Yet the former Malaysian PM signed off on U.S. $34 billion of rail, pipeline and other deals with Chinese state companies, to be funded by Chinese banks and built by Chinese workers as part of President Xi Jinping's One Belt, One Road infrastructure project.</p>
<p>The project is controversial, with U.S. officials and other overseas analysts warning that Beijing is using the project to advance its strategic and military goals, while getting other developing countries deeply in its debt and boosting its hold over their governments.</p>
<p>Bruce Lui, senior journalism lecturer at the University of Hong Kong, said the offer reflects Communist Party attitudes to journalism.</p>
<p>"It is totally normal for the mainland authorities ... to monitor journalists, to obstruct their work, and to hide [things] from them," Lui said. "If this report is accurate, it would be entirely in keeping with [those methods]."</p>
<p>"There are many areas in which 'one country' trumps 'two systems'," he said, referring to China's promises that Hong Kong would remain a separate jurisdiction under the "one country, two systems" formula after the 1997 handover to Beijing, however.</p>
<p>Democratic Party lawmaker James To, deputy chair of the security committee of Hong Kong's Legislative Council (LegCo), said the report was a matter of concern.</p>
<p>"The central government does have the ability to act in this way in Hong Kong, but under Hong Kong's system, it has no right to go looking for journalists' details, whether or not it's to advance their diplomatic interests," To said.</p>
<p>"This is a crime under laws governing the use of communications," he said.</p>
<p>RFA contacted the offices of chief executive Carrie Lam and the secretary for security John Lee on Tuesday, but neither had responded to requests for comment by the time of writing.</p>
<p><b>‘The lovely people at Wen Wei Po’</b></p>
<p>The revelations come after Kevin Carrico, a lecturer at Macquarie University in Australia, reported being followed throughout a trip to Hong Kong by the pro-Beijing <i>Wen Wei Po</i> newspaper, which ran a front-page story about his visits to local political figures.</p>
<p>"The lovely people at <i>Wen Wei Po</i> stalked me for a week and wrote a cover story about me once I left HK," Carrico wrote after returning to Australia.</p>
<p>"Another overseas ‘pro-independence’ scholar comes to Hong Kong to teach ‘independence theory’ in the name of tourism!" the headline read.</p>
<p>Hong Kong was formerly regarded as a bastion of press freedom, with many international news organizations stationing regional editors and correspondents in the city.</p>
<p>But the rejection last October of a visa renewal application from Victor Mallet, the <i>Financial Times</i>' Hong Kong-based Asia editor, after he hosted a lunch event at the Foreign Correspondents' Club (FCC) at which pro-independence politician Andy Chan was the speaker signaled a sea change for journalists there.</p>
<p>Mallet defended the FCC event in the face of open criticism and requests to cancel Chan's appearance. His visa renewal was later rejected without explanation, and he was given just seven days to leave the city, and later turned away when he tried to re-enter as a visitor.</p>
<p>Alvin Yeung, who heads Hong Kong's Civic party, called on the Hong Kong government to clarify the situation.</p>
<p>"We are talking about public security officials in mainland China, who think that they are free to enter ordinary offices and homes in Hong Kong to set up surveillance," Yeung said. "Does the Hong Kong government know nothing about this, or is it acquiescing in their actions?"</p>
<p>Yeung said agents of the Chinese state have already engaged in suspected cross-border law enforcement, citing the case of U.K. national Lee Po, who was removed from his place of work in Hong Kong in 2015 and later showed up in police detention across the internal border in mainland China.</p>
<p>"If this report is true, it indicates that [the Chinese authorities] couldn't care less about 'one country, two systems'," he said.</p>
<p>A U.S. State Department policy report on Hong Kong said last May that the ruling Chinese Communist Party says one thing and does another when it comes to Hong Kong, often acting in ways that are inconsistent with the city's promised freedom to govern its own affairs.</p>
<p>Repeated comments from Chinese officials asserting the supremacy of the Chinese constitution last year served to "dilute" the concept of a "high degree of autonomy" enshrined in the 1984 Sino-British handover treaty and the city's mini-constitution, the Basic Law, the report said.</p>
<p><b>Murky circumstances</b></p>
<p>Hong Kong's Causeway Bay Books store made world headlines in 2015 when five of its staff members went missing in the course of two or three months.</p>
<p>Swedish national Gui Minhai, who headed the Mighty Current publishing house that owned Causeway Bay Books, "disappeared" under murky circumstances from his holiday home in Pattaya, Thailand on October 2015, only to reappear in China "confessing" on video to a decade-old alleged drunk-driving offense.</p>
<p>He now faces further charges of spying after being snatched from a train as he traveled to Beijing in the company of Swedish diplomats.</p>
<p>In the months that followed, store manager and British national Lee Bo, 65, went missing from his workplace in Hong Kong, and the group's general manager Lui Bo (also spelled Lui Por) and colleagues Cheung Chi-ping and Lam Wing-kei were also all detained.</p>
<p>They later resurfaced in China, which accused them of selling "banned books" in Hong Kong to customers across the internal border in mainland China.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Lau Siu-fung for RFA's Cantonese Service, and by Gao Feng for the Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Myanmar Vows to Crush Arakan Army, Urges Locals to Cut Support</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmar-vows-to-crush-arakan-army-01072019171931.html</guid>
        <description>Rakhine politicians, however, call on the central government to heed local concerns in the strife-torn region. </description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 22:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmar-vows-to-crush-arakan-army-01072019171931.html/myanmar-border-guard-police-buthidaung-rakhine-jan7-2019.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[A Myanmar border guard policeman guards a police outpost in Buthidaung township, amid a surge of violence in western Myanmar's Rakhine state, Jan. 7, 2019. ]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Myanmar’s leaders on Monday vowed to “crush” an insurgency in western Rakhine state by the Arakan Army (AA), demanding that ethnic Rakhines end support for the armed group that killed 13 policeman in coordinated attacks during the country’s Independence Day last week.</p>
<p>Zaw Htay, director general of President Win Myint's office, said Myanmar’s de facto leader State Counselor Aung San Suu Kyi discussed the AA’s attacks during a meeting on national security held with the president, military chief Senior General Min Aung Hlaing, and other cabinet members.</p>
<p>“The president’s office has instructed the military to launch an operation to crush the terrorists,” he told a news conference in the capital Naypyidaw.</p>
<p>“The Myanmar government has denounced the AA as a terrorist organization and ordered the military to implement effective counter-insurgency measures against it,” he said.</p>
<p>Zaw Htay also said that the AA’s attacks were a “stab in the back” and that political differences divisions should be resolved through discussion.</p>
<p>On Friday, Myanmar’s Independence Day, members of the AA used both light and heavy weapons to attack four police outposts in Buthidaung township, killing 13 officers and injuring nine others.</p>
<p>Zaw Htay accused the AA of having ties to the Arakan Rohingya Salvation Army (ARSA), a Muslim militant group that in August 2017 launched deadly assaults on 30 police outposts and an army base in northern Rakhine state, triggering a brutal military crackdown that killed thousands and drove more than 725,000 Rohingya across the border to Bangladesh.</p>
<p>“We have had information about ARSA, and we learned earlier that the AA would attack police posts,” he said. “We reviewed why our police posts were attacked and have discussed some plans to work on in the region, but we can’t give you the details now.”</p>
<p>Zaw Htay said he believes the attacks are the outcome of meetings between the AA and ARSA in July, but he did not offer any evidence of such contacts between the two mutually hostile groups.</p>
<p>The AA represents the state's Buddhist Rahkine ethnic group, while ARSA is a militant group that purports to speak for Muslim Rohingyas.</p>
<p>AA spokesman Khine Thukha said his group does not have any connections to ARSA and that Zaw Htay’s statements during Monday’s press conference were an attempt by the government and the military to brand the Arakan group a terrorist organization.</p>
<p>Zaw Htay also urged Rakhine lawmakers, youth, and civil society organizations to stop supporting AA rebels for sake of the state’s development.</p>
<p>“Do they want to see a cycle of violence lasting decades?” he asked at the press conference. “I want to tell the Rakhine people who are supporting AA, please don’t think about yourself, but think about your next generation.”</p>
<p><b><div style="width:622px;" class="image-inline captioned">
 <div style="width:622px;">
  <img src="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmar-vows-to-crush-arakan-army-01072019171931.html/myanmar-presidents-office-aa-attacks-in-rakhine-jan7-2019.jpg/image" alt="myanmar-presidents-office-aa-attacks-in-rakhine-jan7-2019.jpg" title="myanmar-presidents-office-aa-attacks-in-rakhine-jan7-2019.jpg" height="350" width="622" />
 </div>
 <div class="image-caption">
    <span style="width:622px;">Myanmar military and government leaders attend a meeting to discuss national security at the Presidential Palace in Naypyidaw, Jan. 7, 2019.</span>
    
            <span class="copyright">Credit: Photo courtesy of Myanmar President's Office</span>
    
    
 </div>
</div>

Army urged to listen to locals</b></p>
<p>Rakhine representatives appeared to be lukewarm to the appeal and called on the central government to listen to local concerns in the state.</p>
<p>Htu May, an Arakan National Party (ANP) lawmaker in the upper house of Rakhine state's parliament, said that the central government and Tatmadaw, as the national military is called, should consider the position of ethnic Rakhine people living in the region to prevent such attacks from recurring.</p>
<p>“I myself as an ethnic Rakhine would like to add that regarding the attacks on Independence Day, the sentiments of ethnic minorities should be taken into account by the Union government and the Tatmadaw,” he said.</p>
<p>“Then, there could be discussions and a solution,” he said. “Incidents like the Independence Day attack could be reduced once the discussions began.”</p>
<p>Tun Aung Kyaw, general secretary of the ANP, said the party was questioning whether the attack on Independence Day was appropriate.</p>
<p>“For warring parties, if one is not an ally, he may be considered an enemy,” he said. “Maybe that’s the reason they launched an attack. We can’t say for sure.”</p>
<p>The AA, which is fighting the Myanmar military for greater autonomy in Rakhine state, attacked the outposts because the government army is using the police for military operations, and the police have threatened area villagers, Khine Thukha told RFA on Friday.</p>
<p>He also said that Arakan soldiers did not intentionally choose Independence Day to carry out the violence.</p>
<p>“We just did what we had to do,” he said. “We didn’t choose Independence Day. It was just a coincidence. There’s no Independence Day for us.”</p>
<p>The Myanmar military declared a four-month unilateral cease-fire on Dec. 21 in five military regions, but it excluded Rakhine state.</p>
<p>Statements by the Myanmar National Human Rights Commission (MNHRC) and ultranationalist Buddhist group Ma Ba Tha on Sunday said the attacks by the AA constituted an act of terrorism.</p>
<p>MNHRC member Yu Lwin Aung pointed out that the armed assaults were deliberately launched during a flag-raising event “to disgrace the nation.”</p>
<p>“If the other side retaliates, then the people will become victims and lose their basic rights,” he said. “It is difficult to stay calm and not fight back. Such violent acts can lead to human rights violations of local ethnics. That’s why we condemn such acts of terrorism.”</p>
<p>Ma Ba Tha’s statement expressed sorrow for the dead and injured policemen and urged the government to take full responsibility for law and order and protect the local population.</p>
<p>Clashes between the Myanmar military and the AA in Kyauktaw, Buthidaung, Rathedaung, and Ponnakyun townships have forced more than 5,000 local residents to leave their homes, according to estimates by locals and the United Nations.</p>
<p>The rebel group reported that a fresh clash with the military occurred around noon on Monday near Doechaung Wa village in Paletwa township.</p>
<p><b>Warning letter and bullet</b></p>
<p>A member of the AA, meanwhile, has sent a warning letter along with a bullet to police officer Kyaw Hla, commander of the Tain Nyo police station in Rakhine’s Mrauk-U township, according to AA spokesman Khine Thukha.</p>
<p>“It could be AA’s lower-level commanders who sent the bullet along with the warning letter to this police officer because he is known as the one who has oppressed local residents,” he said.</p>
<p>RFA contacted Kyaw Kyaw Hla who confirmed that he received the threat and the bullet, but said he could not comment further on the incident because he was busy.</p>
<p>The letter warns him not to disrupt the AA’s Rakhine national affairs activities.</p>
<p>Someone in the AA also sent similar threats to Chit Shar Aung, police chief of Nwa Yone Taung village, and two locals named Nyan Lin and Sit Sit on Dec. 21.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, groups of journalists from domestic and international news outlets have been visiting the areas where the attacks by the AA took place on a Myanmar government-sponsored trip since Jan. 5.</p>
<p>On Monday, a group that included reporters from RFA, Voice of America, Democratic Voice of Burma, Mizzima, and the <i>Myanmar Times</i> traveled by helicopter to Maungdaw township, which borders Buthidaung, along with Lieutenant General Aung Win Oo, chief of the Myanmar Police Force, and Khin Maung Tin, deputy minister of the State Counselor’s Office.</p>
<p>Government officials comforted policemen and their families who were attacked by the AA and offered them money before having a closed-door meeting at Maungdaw district’s General Administrative Office.</p>
<p>“We will not remain silent on these attacks which are a stab in the back,” Aung Win Oo told the police officers. “The Police Force will do what we should together with the military.”</p>
<p>After the meeting, Police Brigadier General Myint Toe, the commander of Border Guard Police Force No. 1, told the reporters about the AA’s attacks on Jan. 4.</p>
<p>The reporters also visited police outposts in Kahtee Hla and Gotepi villages and the No. 3 Border Guard Police Force in Buthidaung, but government authorities didn’t take them to the Kyaung Taung and Nga Myin Taw police posts for security reasons.<br /> <i><b></b></i></p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Wai Mar Tun, Win Ko Ko Latt, and Min Thein Aung for RFA’s Myanmar Service. Translated by Nandar Chann and Khet Mar. Written in English by Roseanne Gerin.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Cambodia’s PM Hun Sen Calls For Political Dialogue at Event Marking End of Khmer Rouge Era</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/cambodia/dialogue-01072019163412.html</guid>
        <description>But he falls short of inviting the now-dissolved main opposition party for talks.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 22:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/cambodia/dialogue-01072019163412.html/cambodia-hun-sen-jan-7-2019-1000.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Cambodia's Prime Minister Hun Sen (C) waves to the crowd during an event marking the 40th anniversary of the end of the Khmer Rouge era at the Olympic Stadium in Phnom Penh, Jan. 7, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Hun Sen's Facebook page]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Sen, during a lavish ruling party celebration Monday to mark the 40th anniversary of the end of the bloody Khmer Rouge era, called for “wider political dialogue” in his country, but fell short of including the now-dissolved opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP).<br /><br />During an event attended by more than 60,000 people at Phnom Penh’s Olympic Stadium, Hun Sen thanked Vietnam for “aiding the struggle to liberate Cambodia and her people from the genocidal regime,” under whose 1975-79 rule an estimated 3 million people are believed to have died.<br /><br />“The timely Jan. 7 [1979] victory saved millions of Cambodian lives who otherwise would have been subjected to death,” he said, suggesting Vietnam had merely aided the Cambodian National Salvation Front in overthrowing the Khmer Rouge, rather than invaded and taken control of the country.<br /><br />“That day reintroduced and revived values, both spiritual and material, of the Khmer nation, brought to an end a dark chapter of Cambodia’s history, and opened a new era for the country—one of independence, freedom, democracy and social progress for its pitiful citizens. We have since provided Cambodian citizens all kinds of rights and freedoms for them to have true control over their own fates.”<br /><br />After Vietnam marched on Phnom Penh, Hanoi administered the country for more than a decade, appointing Hun Sen prime minister and maintaining tens of thousands of troops on the ground.<br /><br />After facing heavy international pressure and enduring significant military casualties, Vietnam withdrew its troops from Cambodia in September 1989 and two years later became a signatory to the Paris Peace Accord, which paved the way for the country to become a democracy.<br /><br />During Monday’s event, Hun Sen also vowed to open Cambodia up to “wider political dialogue between all parties, civil society, and all progressive circles,” but fell short of mentioning the now-dissolved opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP), which was banned by the Supreme Court in November 2017 for its role in an alleged plot to topple the government.<br /><br />The court decision, which also slapped a five-year ban on the political activities of 118 of the CNRP’s senior officials, allowed the ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) to effectively run uncontested in Cambodia’s July 29 general election and win all 125 seats in parliament.<br /><br />Hun Sen said Monday that his government would promote wider political dialogue “to collect intellectual input and human resources from all sources, without discrimination, and to increase the total force for nation-state building and development.”<br /><br />However, he warned against “a history that we cannot let resurface, as it causes national division due to the ambition of politicians who use our citizens as their tools to attain their personal interests without thinking about the fate of the nation.”<br /><br /><b><div style="width:1000px;" class="image-inline captioned">
 <div style="width:1000px;">
  <img src="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/cambodia/dialogue-01072019163412.html/cambodia-parade-jan-7-2019-1000.jpg/image" alt="cambodia-parade-jan-7-2019-1000.jpg" title="cambodia-parade-jan-7-2019-1000.jpg" height="563" width="1000" />
 </div>
 <div class="image-caption">
    <span style="width:1000px;">Marchers parade through Phnom Penh's Olympic Stadium at an event marking the 40th anniversary of the end of the Khmer Rouge era in Phnom Penh, Jan. 7, 2019. Credit: Hun Sen's Facebook page</span>
    
            <span class="copyright"> </span>
    
    
 </div>
</div>

Political dialogue</b><br /><br />Speaking to RFA’s Khmer Service after the ceremony, senior CNRP official and former lawmaker Um Sam An rejected the idea that Hun Sen is seeking national reconciliation.<br /><br />“Even if he intends to promote comprehensive dialogue, he will not hold talks with all political parties—particularly the CNRP or civil society organizations that work transparently, fairly, and independent of the government,” he said.<br /><br />“He only will hold dialogue with minor political parties that serve as his puppets.”<br /><br />When asked for clarification about Hun Sen’s statement, CPP spokesperson Chhim Phal Vearun told RFA that it should not be taken as an invitation to dialogue with the CNRP.<br /><br />“This doesn’t suggest that [dialogue] will be held with the now-defunct party—Hun Sen referred only to parties with legal status under Cambodian law,” he said.<br /><br />Veteran political analyst Lao Mong Hay told RFA that Hun Sen was continuing to isolate himself from the international community by refusing to reinstate the CNRP and restoring political rights to its officials.<br /><br />Since the election, the U.S. has announced visa bans on individuals seen as limiting democracy in the country, as part of a series of measures aimed at pressuring Cambodia to reverse course, and the European Union, which was the second biggest trade partner of Cambodia in 2017, has said it will drop a preferential trade scheme for Cambodian exports based on the country’s election environment.<br /><br />Meanwhile, Soeng Sen Karuna, spokesman for local rights group Adhoc, applauded Hun Sen’s promise, noting that civil society has faced difficulties in working with the government at all levels, and has even been accused of staging a revolution for campaigning on behalf of human rights and efforts to ensure free and fair elections.<br /><br />“We welcome his remarks, but we don’t know from now on whether they will be effectively implemented,” he said.<br /><br />“The Interior Ministry has already issued a notification to open the space for civil society, but in practice, things have not been improving. For instance, we were obstructed from holding an event to celebrate International Human Rights Day on Jan. 3.”<br /><br /><b>Liberation or invasion</b><br /><br />Hun Sen’s remarks about Vietnam also drew condemnation on Monday from observers who called Jan. 7 is a day of “invasion,” rather than liberation.<br /><br />Acting CNRP President Sam Rainsy, who is living in self-imposed exile to avoid a string of convictions by courts seen as beholden to Hun Sen, called the prime minister a “usurper” who was first “installed by the invading Vietnamese Communist army in 1979.”<br /><br />“He has since clung to power through election manipulation, terror and violence,” he said, in a message posted to his Facebook account.<br /><br />Ly Srey Sros, a youth political analyst, told RFA that Jan. 7 is a day “with both good and bad connotations” for Cambodia’s youth.<br /><br />“Vietnam’s intervention in Cambodia can be considered a success story for Cambodian citizens in that they were able to escape the genocidal regime, but we must admit that based on international law, such an intervention was a violation of Cambodia’s sovereignty,” she said.<br /><br />Sophal Ear, associate professor of World Affairs at Occidental College in Los Angeles, called Vietnam’s intervention “both a liberation and catastrophe for Cambodia.”<br /><br />“It brought liberation from the Khmer Rouge, but it also brought to power a group of individuals who, 40 years later, are still in power,” he said.<br /><br />“In that time, Cambodia went from a Vietnamese colony to a Chinese colony,” he added, referring to Beijing’s increasing influence in the Southeast Asian nation.<br /><br />In the lead up to Monday’s celebration, hundreds of ethnic Cambodians living in Australia and the U.S. staged “anti-Jan. 7 Day” protests over the weekend, referring to the anniversary as a “day of grief” marking a “foreign occupation” of Cambodia.<br /><br />Animosity between Vietnam and Cambodia goes back centuries, but was heightened by the Vietnamese war in 1979, and accusations over the demarcation of the border between the two countries have become a prominent feature in Cambodian politics as Hun Sen’s opponents have attempted to paint the strong man as a tool of the Vietnamese.<br /><br />Hanoi’s state-run Vietnam News Agency reported that the two countries held a ceremony on Jan. 4 in the Vietnamese capital to mark the “victory of the southwest border defense war and the joint victory on January 7 of Vietnam and Cambodia over the genocidal regime.” <br /><br /><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Sovannarith Keo. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>China Actively Targeting Internet Users For Browsing Overseas Websites, Social Media</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/vpn-punish-01072019151116.html</guid>
        <description>Police are handing out administrative punishments for 'using illegal channels to access the international internet.'
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 20:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/vpn-punish-01072019151116.html/vpn-punish.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[A man uses a computer in an internet cafe in the Chinese capital Beijing, June 1, 2017. ]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Authorities in China are actively pursuing internet users who use</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> circumvention tools to avoid the complex system of blocks, filters and</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> human censorship known collectively as the Great Firewall.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Police in Rongchang district of the southwestern megacity of Chongqing</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> handed an official summons and warning to internet user Huang</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Chengcheng for "setting up and using illegal channels to access the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> international internet."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Huang was held for eight hours of questioning on Jan. 4, his phone</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> scanned, and his posts to overseas social media sites gathered by</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> police for use as evidence.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Police said Huang's posts had "seriously contravened laws and</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> regulations," and warned him not to use circumvention tools again,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> according to the Civil Rights and Livelihood Watch rights website.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">An internet user surnamed Liu who frequently uses virtual private</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> networks (VPNs) to scale the Great Firewall said the ruling Chinese</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Communist Party doesn't want its citizens to have free access to</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> non-government sources of information.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"VPNs are specifically designed to get around China's Great Firewall,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> meaning that we can see how different the news is in China, where it</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> is tightly controlled, to the U.S., where the flow of information is</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> relatively free," Liu said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"[We can also see] by comparison how they are more advanced than we</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> are in terms of the information economy and in terms of democracy," he</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> said. "There is going to be a backlash; an inevitable side-effect of</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> the suppression of news, and also an expression of the curiosity that</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> oppressed people have about the outside world."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Meanwhile, police in the southern province of Guangdong issued an</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> administrative punishment to an internet user surnamed Zhu for</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> "setting up and using illegal channels to access the international</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> internet."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">According to the official WeChat social media account of the Shaoguan</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> municipal police department, Zhu was fined 1,000 yuan on Dec. 27 for</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> his use of the Lantern Pro app to circumvent government censorship, in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> violation of articles 6 and 14 of China's "Interim provisions for the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> management of computer information networks (international internet)."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">A duty officer who answered the phone at the Shaoguan police</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> department declined to comment, referring inquiries to the internet</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> police.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">But an officer who answered the phone at the Shaoguan municipal</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> internet police said they didn't know anything about Zhu's case.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><b><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Scaling the wall</span></b></p>
<p><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Rights lawyer Liang Xiaojun said fining people for viewing the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> overseas internet is "ridiculous," but that not everyone in China is</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> concerned about it.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"Actually they are forbidding people from circumventing the Great</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Firewall in order to control their thoughts," Liang said. "But many</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> people in China think that they don't need to scale the Great Firewall</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> to view things outside ... there are so many different types of</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> information on Weibo, and that's enough."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"Others don't need to scale the wall, so they don't think there's a problem.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">An internet user surnamed Wu from the southwestern province of Sichuan</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> said the government doesn't want people to see anything that</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> challenges the official version of the news.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"They are afraid that we will be able to learn more," she said. "There</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> are a lot of things we can't even see."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">An internet user who asked for anonymity said: "The Chinese Communist</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Party is trying to control all aspects of society to maintain its</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> political power. It monitors people's thoughts and behavior, and</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> suppresses the vitality of the whole of society."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Over the last two decades, China’s Great Firewall has grown into an</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> alarmingly effective apparatus of censorship and surveillance,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> according to the 2018 Freedom on the Net report published by Freedom</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> House.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"Internet controls within China reached new extremes in 2018 with the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> implementation of the sweeping Cybersecurity Law and upgrades to</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> surveillance technology," the report said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">It said Beijing is also seeking to propagate its model of online</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> censorship overseas by conducting large-scale trainings of foreign</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> officials, providing technology to authoritarian governments, and</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> demanding that international companies abide by its content</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> regulations even when operating outside of China.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"These trends present an existential threat to the future of the open</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> internet and prospects for greater democracy around the globe," the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> report said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><i><b><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Reported by Qiao Long for RFA's Mandarin Service, and by Ma Lap-hak</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> and Fok Leung-kiu for the Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Luisetta Mudie.</span></b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>China Plans to 'Sinicize' Islam as Muslims Warn of Eradication Campaign</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/islam-01072019124436.html</guid>
        <description>The government-backed Islamic Association says the religion must be compatible with President Xi Jinping's political thought.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 18:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/islam-01072019124436.html/china-seminar2-010719.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[The China Islamic Association holds a seminar on "The Orientation of Islam in China 2018-2022," Jan. 5, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Moosely Online]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>China is developing a five-year plan for the "sinicization" of Islam, according to the country's government-backed China Islamic Association.<br /><br />Representatives from local Islamic associations from eight provinces and regions, including Beijing, Shanghai, Hunan, Yunnan, and Qinghai, discussed the plan at a meeting on Saturday, according to a report on the association's official website.<br /><br />The plan will focus on requiring mosques to to uphold "core values of socialism, traditional culture, laws and regulations," Association president Yang Faming told the meeting, which was organized by the ruling Chinese Communist Party's United Front Work Department, which is tasked with co-opting groups and individuals outside the party to endorse its message.<br /><br />Mosques will be told to "guide, mobilize and inspire" Chinese Muslims with lectures and training sessions on such topics, and which uphold the spirit of a sinicized Islam by using examples of notable figures, Yang said.<br /><br />The move comes after Chinese authorities in the southwestern province of Yunnan raided and forcibly evicted local ethnic minority Hui Muslims from three mosques at the end of last month, saying they were engaged in "illegal religious activities."<br /><br />Local Hui Muslims blamed the crackdown on the local Islamic Association's compliance with government directives.<br /><br />U.S.-based Muslim student activist Sulaiman Gu said the "sinicization" program had been designed to target Hui Muslims in particular.<br /><br />"The sinicization of Islam is mostly targeted at Hui Muslims," Gu told RFA on Monday. "[They] know very well that there's no point in using the rhetoric of anti-terrorism or separatism to justify it, but it's still a form of cultural genocide."<br /><br />"The cultural genocide of the Hui Muslims is nothing new: it's been a core government policy," he said. "About 60 years ago, they persecuted the Hui scholarly elite, and started a campaign to raise pigs among the Hui."<br /><br />Gu said a period of relative peace had ensued for the Hui Muslims, but likened it to a frog sitting in warm water that will eventually boil.<br /><br />"Now they are just adding logs to the fire," he said.<br /><br /><b>A fundamental challenge</b><br /><br />Dilxat Raxit, spokesman for exile group the World Uyghur Congress, said the sinicization campaign is utterly coercive.<br /><br />"China has always seen the beliefs of Islam as a fundamental challenge to Communist Party rule," he said. "There is a plan; there's an aim here."<br /><br />"The so-called Islamic Associations have no respect for religious beliefs or customs," Raxit said. "They are planning to wipe them out for good."<br /><br />An ethnic Kazakh Muslim from the Aksu region of Xinjiang who gave only a single name, Yati, agreed.<br /><br />"The meaning of the sinicization of Islam is that, in future, there will be no more Islam," he said. "It's a Chinese Communist Party euphemism for their plan to erase the Hui, and their religion."<br /><br />"Eventually, there won't be any Muslims left [in China]," Yati said.<br /><br />Repeated calls to the national headquarters of the China Islamic Association rang unanswered during office hours on Monday.<br /><br />The <i>Global Times </i>newspaper, sister paper to Communist Party mouthpiece the <i>People's Daily</i>, said a set of guidelines for the sinicization plan would be released soon.<br /><br />"China will soon release an outline on the sinicization of Islam, with Islamic communities urged to uphold the sinicization of their religion by improving their political stance and following the [ruling Chinese Communist] Party's leadership," the paper said.<br /><br /><b>Religious violence, nationalism</b><br /><br />In an opinion article, the paper said a global religious revival and "immigrants of different religious beliefs" had caused social conflicts, citing the anti-migrant rhetoric of Italy's hard-line interior minister Matteo Salvini.<br /><br />"Fundamentalism has caused more religious violence and religious nationalism is threatening countries' legitimate governments and leading to social instability," it said, without giving examples.<br /><br />"In Xinjiang, religious extremism has been effectively addressed. Peace and order have eventually been restored to the region," the paper said, in an oblique reference to widespread criticism of the mass internment of at least one million Muslims in camps in the northwestern region.<br /><br />Mass detentions in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region (XUAR) have drawn significant attention from the international community, and particularly from the U.S., where lawmakers have called for access to the camps and proposed sanctions against officials and entities in China deemed responsible for abusing the rights of ethnic Uyghurs and other Muslim minorities.<br /><br />While Beijing initially denied the existence of re-education camps, the chairman of the XUAR government, Shohrat Zakir, told China’s official Xinhua news agency in October that the facilities are an effective tool to protect the country from terrorism and provide vocational training for Uyghurs.<br /><br />But reporting by RFA’s Uyghur Service and other media organizations has shown that those held in the camps are detained against their will, are subjected to political indoctrination and rough treatment at the hands of their overseers, and endure poor diets and unhygienic conditions in the often overcrowded facilities. <br /><br />The atmosphere is more like a prison than any kind of school, multiple sources say.<br /><br /><b>'Made-in-China Islam'</b><br /><br />"The Chinese government is attempting to create a made-in-China Islam based on its atheistic and communist ideology," said Uyghur American Association president Ilshat Hassan, speaking to RFA.<br /><br />"The Chinese government's final solution is to forcibly assimilate the Uyghur Muslims into China's atheistic society by eradicating the Uyghur Islam, a unique cultural phenomenon blended with the Uyghur people's centuries-long peaceful traditions and cultures."<br /><br />"[China's policies] will justify the criminalization of Uyghur Islam," agreed Uyghur Human Rights Project chairman Nury Turkel.<br /><br />"This further indicates that the Chinese Communist Party has intensified its own war on Uyghur Islam. Ironically, the CCP is trying to utilize a religious belief that it is inherently against for political purposes."<br /><br />Adrian Zenz, a lecturer in social research methods at the Germany-based European School of Culture and Theology, has said that some 1.1 million people are or have been detained in the camps—equating to 10 to 11 percent of the adult Muslim population of the XUAR.<br /><br />In November 2018, Scott Busby, the deputy assistant secretary in the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights and Labor at the U.S. Department of State, said there are "at least 800,000 and possibly up to a couple of million" Uyghurs and others detained at re-education camps in the XUAR without charges, citing U.S. intelligence assessments.<br /><br />Citing credible reports, U.S. lawmakers Marco Rubio and Chris Smith, who head the bipartisan Congressional-Executive Commission on China, recently called the situation in the XUAR "the largest mass incarceration of a minority population in the world today."<br /><i><b><br />Reported by Qiao Long for RFA's Mandarin Service and by Alim Seytoff for the Uyghur Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>China's Economic Stimulus Spurs Climate Costs</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/commentaries/energy_watch/chinas-economic-stimulus-spurs-climate-costs-01072019105749.html</guid>
        <description>A new wave of infrastructure projects will boost coal demand, experts warn.</description>
        
	        <author>An analysis by Michael Lelyveld</author>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 16:16:12 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/commentaries/energy_watch/chinas-economic-stimulus-spurs-climate-costs-01072019105749.html/china-passenger-high-speed-rail-shenzhen-sept23-2018.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[A passenger takes a selfie next to the first train of the Guangzhou-Shenzhen-Hong Kong Express Rail Link after it arrives in Shenzhen, southeastern China's Guangdong province, Sept. 23, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>China's plan to revive its economy with new stimulus measures may spell trouble for energy forecasts and global efforts to control climate change.</p>
<p>As the government tries to stop the slowdown in growth over the coming year, reports suggest that it will revert to familiar formulas, pumping up the economy with new infrastructure projects backed by credit and debt.</p>
<p>A statement following last month's annual Central Economic Work Conference made clear that the government will "channel more energy into weak areas, including infrastructure."</p>
<p>The National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC), the country's top planning agency, has already sped up approvals of transportation sector projects, the official English-language <i>China Daily</i> reported on Dec. 18.</p>
<p>The value of 147 projects approved in the third quarter reached 697.7 billion yuan (U.S. $101.1 billion), rising nearly fivefold over the previous period, the paper said.</p>
<p>A provincial NDRC official was quoted as saying that local governments have prepared "a large number of projects that are able to play a role in stabilizing the economy."</p>
<p>Bloomberg News reported that the work conference statement "signals that China is ratcheting up the limited, targeted stimulus approach used during 2018," while stopping short of spending that would weaken the currency and the debt-control campaign.</p>
<p>Other reports raise concerns that the stimulus may not be so limited, renewing memories of the 4-trillion yuan (U.S. $579-billion) project binge in 2008-2009. The building boom buoyed the economy through the global recession but left it mired in pollution and debt.</p>
<p>The push for new projects has raised similar concerns about rapid and wasteful investment.</p>
<p>China is expected to build hundreds of new general aviation airports by 2020, the Chinese Communist Party's flagship paper <i>People's Daily</i> reported last month.</p>
<p>And after a period of restraint in approving new subway projects, China's "building binge is back on track," the <i>Financial Times</i> said.</p>
<p>The subway splurge includes 95 billion yuan (U.S. $13.8 billion) for four new lines in Suzhou city of eastern Jiangsu province, despite doubtful ridership, the <i>FT</i> reported.</p>
<p>On Dec. 19, the NDRC also approved 298 billion yuan (U.S. $43.3 billion) worth of urban rail projects for nearby Shanghai, state media said.</p>
<p>On Dec. 26, Transport Minister Li Xiaopeng said that 1.8 trillion yuan (U.S. $261.7 billion) is expected to be invested in road and rail infrastructure projects in 2019, <i>China Daily</i> reported.</p>
<p><b>Effect on coal consumption</b></p>
<p>The headlong rush for new projects is bound to have consequences for coal consumption, which rose 0.4 percent in 2017, the highest rate since 2013, according to the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS).</p>
<p>Given last year's stimulus activity, the 2018 consumption figure for coal, China's main source of power, is likely to be higher. New infrastructure projects will boost demand for energy-intensive products including steel and cement.</p>
<p>Last month, an international group of climate scientists at the Global Carbon Project projected that China's coal consumption in 2018 climbed 4.5 percent, driving carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions up 4.7 percent.</p>
<p>The group identified China's increased coal use as the leading factor in last year's worldwide rise in CO2 by 2.7 percent.</p>
<p>"The biggest change in CO2 emissions in 2018 compared with 2017 is a substantial increase in both energy consumption and CO2 emissions in China, ... driven largely by growth in heavy manufacturing," the group said.</p>
<p>In the first 11 months of 2018, raw coal production jumped 5.4 percent from a year earlier, the NBS said. China produces and consumes about half of the world's coal.</p>
<p>The Global Carbon Project's outlook contrasts sharply with forecasts of a gradual decline in China's coal demand over the next several years.</p>
<p>In its medium-term coal forecast released last month, the Paris-based International Energy Agency (IEA) estimated that demand will edge down at a compound average annual rate of 0.5 percent over the period from 2016 through 2023.</p>
<p>According to forecast data from the IEA's Coal 2018 report, China's coal demand will drop slightly by about 0.2 percent in 2019 compared with estimates for 2017.</p>
<p>The figures are important for climate change projections because they may support arguments advanced over the last several years that China's coal consumption has already peaked.</p>
<p>The IEA data seems to suggest that the turnaround in China's coal growth is already underway.</p>
<p>But it is unclear whether the IEA's projections reflect the extent of the stimulus policies that are now being pursued by the government.</p>
<p>"The government is very worried about the economy, which appears to be growing at a rate well below their planned 'new normal,'" said Philip Andrews-Speed, a China energy expert at National University of Singapore.</p>
<p>Andrews-Speed cited the sudden wave of new airport and urban rail projects, which are likely to drive coal demand for power and building materials.</p>
<p>"Coal consumption is almost certain to grow at a rate well in excess of the IEA's estimate," said Andrews-Speed.</p>
<p>"The only way in which the growth could be kept close to the IEA's estimate is if the government is very effective at suppressing coal-fired power generation in favor of hydro-electric, nuclear, wind, and solar power. But its track record in this respect is not great," he said.</p>
<p><b><div style="width:622px;" class="image-inline captioned">
 <div style="width:622px;">
  <img src="https://www.rfa.org/english/commentaries/energy_watch/chinas-economic-stimulus-spurs-climate-costs-01072019105749.html/china-shanghai-metro-tunnel-construction-july11-2017.jpg/image" alt="china-shanghai-metro-tunnel-construction-july11-2017.jpg" title="china-shanghai-metro-tunnel-construction-july11-2017.jpg" height="350" width="622" />
 </div>
 <div class="image-caption">
    <span style="width:622px;">A Chinese worker (L) eats lunch inside a tunnel at the construction site of Line 14 of the Shanghai metro system in Shanghai, July 11, 2017.</span>
    
            <span class="copyright">Credit: AFP</span>
    
    
 </div>
</div>

A rebound in coal use?</b></p>
<p>In response to RFA questions, IEA senior energy analyst Carlos Fernandez Alvarez said that China's air quality policies have removed some coal consumption from the residential and small industrial sectors, thanks in part to increases in natural gas.</p>
<p>Efforts to reduce coal in those sectors have been partially offset by higher electricity demand, but the IEA estimates that more coal has been removed than added.</p>
<p>"This is the reason (for) our forecast," Fernandez Alvarez said in an email.</p>
<p>But he also warned that new stimulus policies could lead to increased coal consumption.</p>
<p>"If you put on top of it a fiscal stimulus supporting power consumption and other heavy industries (steel, cement, etc.), we could see a rebound in coal use in China and, therefore, in the world," he said.</p>
<p>Fernandez Alvarez sees a repeat of the 2008-2009 stimulus effects as unlikely.</p>
<p>"The current conditions in China are very different from 2008-2009," he said.</p>
<p>"The energy sector is much more efficient, the power mix is more diversified and the economy is more mature.</p>
<p>Therefore, the strong growth of the first decade is very unlikely," Fernandez Alvarez said.</p>
<p>But a new stimulus program would still have significant consequences.</p>
<p>"If you run the numbers, coal consumed in China represents 14 percent of global primary energy, and hence, it is the largest energy source in a country by far. Therefore, what happens in Chinese coal is pivotal for the energy and CO2 emissions trends in the world," Fernandez Alvarez said.</p>
<p>According to the IEA forecast, worldwide coal demand will grow at an average annual rate of 0.2 percent through 2023 with the biggest percentage increases coming in India and Southeast Asia.</p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 </channel>
 
</rss>