<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
 

 

 <channel>
    <title>RFA Home</title>
     <language>en</language>
    <description>
        
            RFA is a private, nonprofit corporation that broadcasts news and information to listeners in Asian countries where full, accurate, and timely news reports are unavailable.
        
    </description>
    <link>https://www.rfa.org/english</link>
    <copyright>Radio Free Asia</copyright>

	 
	 <atom:link href="https://www.rfa.org/english/rss2.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
     

	 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Children Suffer Brain Damage From Seasonal Flu in China's Guangdong</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/flu-brain-01102019121219.html</guid>
        <description>Local newspaper reports several cases of brain damage in children fighting influenza in the provincial capital, Guangzhou.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 17:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/flu-brain-01102019121219.html/flu-info.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Undated file photo of a child being examined in a Guangdong medical clinic, amid an outbreak of seasonal influenza cases in the southern Chinese province that are resulting in brain damage in previously healthy child patients.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Guangzhou Internet Information Office.]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Health authorities in the southern Chinese province of Guangdong are</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> battling a wave of seasonal influenza cases that are resulting in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> brain damage in previously healthy child patients, local media</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> reported.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">While the overall number of confirmed cases of influenza has fallen</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> compared with last year, there has been an increase in the number of</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> notifications of necrotizing encephalitis, a complication from viral</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> fever sometimes found in children, reports said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">The Women and Children's Medical Center in Guangdong's provincial</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> capital Guangzhou was overwhelmed with children suffering from the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> seasonal flu, with at least five confirmed cases of necrotizing</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> encephalitis reported in the facility, Guangzhou's Southern Metropolis</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Daily newspaper reported.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">One three-year-old is in a long-term coma after developing damage to</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> their central nervous system after a two-week hospitalization for H1N1</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> flu, the paper said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">It cited local medical personnel as saying that the virus -- once</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> known for attacking the lungs of patients and causing pneumonia -- may</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> have mutated from previous years to a form that attacks the central</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> nervous system.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">The parent of a primary schooler in Guangzhou said many of her child's</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> classmates were off sick with influenza, and the school had ordered</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> sick children to remain at home to prevent further transmission of the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> virus.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"There have been a lot of cases of influenza at the hospital lately,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> and I've been teaching my kid that we don't go to as many public</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> places when there is an outbreak of this kind," the parent said. "You</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> can pick it up in the hospital, on the streets, and prevention is</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> everything when it comes to the flu."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Guangzhou-based rights activist Zhang Weichu, who is also a medical</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> doctor, said the fact that China's usually tightly controlled media is</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> reporting the story is in itself a cause for concern.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"In the past, these things were not generally reported," Zhang told</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> RFA. "So is the real situation actually more serious than the report</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> says?"</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">She said the report may be hinting at a mutation in the H1N1 virus</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> itself, which could constitute a public health crisis.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><b><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Improving the warning system</span></b></p>
<p><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">According to Zhang, China's health authorities improved their disease</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> reporting and public information mechanisms after the Severe Acute</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Respiratory Syndrom (SARS) epidemic of 2002-2003 led to thousands of</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> infections and more than 700 confirmed deaths worldwide, but there is</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> still room for improvement to the system.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Wang Yuedan, deputy director of the Department of Immunology at Peking</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> University School of Medicine, said that there has been no evidence</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> that the virus had mutated yet, however.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"There have been no relevant warnings issued by the U.S. Centers for</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Disease Control and Prevention, the World Health Organization (WHO) or</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> the CDCs in China, so it probably hasn't," Wang said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">He said a shortage of influenza vaccines is unlikely to be the culprit</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> behind the reported complications, either.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"Many cases wouldn't have been covered by the strains in the vaccines</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> anyway, so the current situation has very little to do with the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> reduction in vaccine supply," Wang said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">The <i>Southern Metropolis Daily</i> cited Women and Children Medical Center</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> deputy director Xu Wei as saying that the center had confirmed 300</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> cases of influenza in the first week of 2019, half the number reported</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> during the same period last year.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">However, Beijing CDC said it expects the flu to remain highly active</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> in the next few weeks.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Acute necrotizing encephalopathy is form of brain damage that usually</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> follows an acute febrile disease, mostly those caused by viruses,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> according to the U.S. National Institutes of Health website.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"The symptoms of the viral infection (fever, respiratory infection,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> and gastroenteritis, among others) are followed by seizures,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> disturbance of consciousness that may rapidly progress to a coma,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> liver problems, and neurological deficits," the website said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">It said the disease is caused by both environmental and genetic</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> factors, and usually develops secondary to viral infections like flu</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> or herpes.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Sufferers have brain lesions affecting the thalami, brain stem,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> cerebral white matter, and cerebellum, it said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><i><b><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Reported by Wong Lok-to for RFA's Cantonese Service, and by Gao Feng</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> for the Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</span></b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Laos’ Garment Industry Faces Severe Labor Shortage</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/laos/lao-garment-workers-thailand-01102019101304.html</guid>
        <description>Workers leave Laos for higher pay and lower expenses in Thailand.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 15:16:26 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/laos/lao-garment-workers-thailand-01102019101304.html/lao-garment-worker.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[lao-garment-worker]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Garment factories in Laos are experiencing labor shortages as workers are looking to Thailand for greener pastures, sources say.</p>
<p>A factory manager in the capital Vientiane who requested anonymity told RFA’s Lao Service earlier this month, “According to [results] of a survey we need about 10,000 more workers.”</p>
<p>The shortage is the result of relatively low wages in Laos compared to what workers in the same industry can earn in neighboring Thailand.</p>
<p>“Some factories have closed because of labor shortages,” said a factory worker in the capital. “They have a limited budget. So since they can’t pay more, workers are leaving,” the worker added.</p>
<p>An owner of a large garment factory in Vientiane said her factory is always running short on labor. She said the competition is high and workers frequently leave for other factories that pay more, or they leave the country to work in Thailand, where they can make twice as much.</p>
<p>She said the factory can’t afford to offer higher wages.</p>
<p>A representative of the Lao Garment Industry Association in early December reported that over the past three years, the number of garment factories in Laos decreased from 92 to 78. The representative blamed labor shortages as one of the major causes.</p>
<p>“Salaries are too low,” said a young woman in the capital, adding, “If you get only $120 a month, all of that goes to food and shelter.</p>
<p>“It’s not worth it. People who work in the garment industry [here in Laos] are those who have no other choice,” she said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a Lao woman in her thirties who has been living in Thailand for several years said, “I came here because I didn’t have [enough] money to continue my education.”</p>
<p>“I can’t work in Laos because wages are too low. My mother is old and poor, living in a small hut. I want to help her, so that’s why I came here,” she said.</p>
<p>She explained that she earns twice what she could in Laos, adding “Don’t forget that living costs are lower in Thailand.”</p>
<p>The head of the human resources department of a garment factory in Laos’ Savannakhet province said that finding the labor isn’t as difficult as keeping it.</p>
<p>“We recruit workers from rural areas, but once they’ve been with us for one or two years, they leave for Thailand,” the HR officer said.</p>
<p>Seven years ago, the labor and social welfare ministry reported that more than 200,000 Laotians were working in Thailand. Estimates for 2018 suggest that this figure has since doubled.</p>
<p>To combat labor shortages, some factories are offering perks like free housing and kitchens for workers to prepare their own food.</p>
<p>“It depends on each factory. Many of [our competitors] can’t afford high wages. But some, like mine, can,” said a marketing manager of a factory in the capital.</p>
<p>“That’s why we don’t have any labor shortage problems. As soon as we post that we’re hiring, we get [enough workers].”</p>
<p><strong><i>Reported by RFA's Lao Service. Translated by RFA's Lao Service. Written in English by Eugene Whong.</i></strong></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Bangladesh: No ARSA, Arakan Militant Bases in Country</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/bangladesh-rakhine-01092019195058.html</guid>
        <description>Dhaka slams Myanmar for saying that Rohingya and Arakan rebel groups are operating in Bangladesh.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/bangladesh-rakhine-01092019195058.html/bangladesh-rakhin.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[People displaced by violence between ethnic Rakhine rebels and Myanmar’s army arrive at a camp in Kyauktaw, Rakhine state, Jan. 4, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Bangladesh’s government on Wednesday vehemently denied allegations by neighboring Myanmar that Rohingya and Arakan militants were operating bases on Bangladeshi territory, after officials in Naypyidaw vowed to “crush” Arakan Army insurgents in Rakhine state.</p>
<p>None of these groups were in Bangladesh, nor was the country “harboring any terrorist organization within its soil,” the Bangladeshi Ministry of Foreign Affairs said in a strongly worded statement.<br /><br />“The allegations are totally fake and baseless,” the ministry said.<br /><br />“It is not possible to operate terrorist bases in Bangladesh because of high alertness and effective preventive measures by the security forces” that were in line, it added, with the government’s zero tolerance policy toward such groups.<br /><br />The Arakan Army (AA) last week launched raids on police outposts in Buthidaung township that left 13 policemen dead and nine others injured, officials said. The AA said it lost three of its fighters in the violence. The group is fighting the Myanmar military for greater autonomy in Rakhine and claims to represent the region’s Buddhist Rakhine ethnic group.</p>
<p><strong>Myanmar’s allegations</strong><br /><br /><span>The ministry blasted Myanmar based on comments made by Zaw Htay, the spokesman for the Myanmar’s President’s Office, during a press conference in Naypyidaw on Monday.</span><br /><br /><span>“On the Bangladesh side the Arakan Army has two bases and ARSA has three bases. Therefore, Myanmar army has lodged a complaint with the Bangladesh military attaché over the issue,” Zaw Htay told reporters then. </span><span>The presidential spokesman did not state the source for this information. </span><br /><br /><span>“The Myanmar government has denounced the AA as a terrorist organization and ordered the military to implement effective counter-insurgency measures against it,” he said.</span><br /><br /><span>He also accused the Arakan Army and ARSA of being linked, allegations that were denied by the AA on Tuesday, according to Radio Free Asia.</span><br /><br /><span>“We have had information about ARSA, and we learned earlier that the AA would attack police posts,” Zaw Htay said. “We reviewed why our police posts were attacked and have discussed some plans to work on in the region, but we can’t give you the details now.”</span><br /><br /><span>Zaw Htay said he believed the attacks were the outcome of meetings between the AA and ARSA in July, but he did not offer any evidence of such contacts between the two mutually hostile groups.</span><br /><br />The northwestern corner of Rakhine borders southeastern Bangladesh, where more than 700,000 Muslim Rohingya refugees escaped and sought shelter amid a brutal offensive by Myanmar’s government forces in August 2017.<br /><br />The crackdown that year followed deadly attacks on police and army outposts by rebels with the Arakan Rohingya Salvation Army (ARSA), a separate armed group that purports to be fighting for the stateless and persecuted Rohingya minority.<br /><br />“Bangladesh is also firmly committed not to allow its soil to be used by any dissident group of any neighboring country,” the Bangladeshi statement said, noting that Dhaka had offered to conduct joint patrols with Myanmar to stop alleged militant activities along the shared border.<br /><br />Myanmar did not embrace the offer with enthusiasm, nor did it provide Bangladesh with “specific details and concrete evidence on the alleged terrorist elements and acts,” the ministry added. <br /><br />Referring to the recent fighting with the Arakan Army, the Bangladeshi ministry described the current clashes as “the outcome of Myanmar’s own political and social dilemma.”<br /><br />Bangladesh’s government would “highly appreciate” if the Myanmar government did “not make any endeavor to associate Bangladesh with her internal political puzzle,” the statement went on to say.</p>
<p><strong><i>Reported by BenarNews, an RFA-affiliated online news service.</i></strong></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Jailed Vietnamese Environmental Activist in Declining Health-Brother</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/vietnam/activist-health-01092019170308.html</guid>
        <description>Hoang Duc Binh is suffering rashes from poor hygiene and life in a dark cell has damaged his sight.  </description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 22:06:05 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/vietnam/sentence-04242018162901.html/vietnam-hoangducbinh-042418.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Hoang Duc Binh (R) is shown at his trial in Vietnam's Nghe An province, Feb. 6, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Jailed Vietnamese activist Hoang Duc Binh is suffering back pain, rashes from poor hygiene and failing eyesight from being in a dark cell in a prison in Quang Nam province, his brother told RFA’s Vietnamese service on Wednesday.</p>
<p>“About two days ago, I received a letter in the mail from Binh telling me that he has his rash again and his back pain has come back and the conditions are getting worse while all medication sent from the family seems not to work,” said his brother Hoang Nguyen.</p>
<p>“In previous meetings or letters, he kept asking us sending him medication from outside because the stuff provided by the prison did not work,” added the brother.</p>
<p>“He got his rash because of the bad hygiene conditions in the prison. His eyes are not good either because he’s been in a dark cell for a long time.”</p>
<p>Hoang Nguyen told RFA in a telephone that Binh had asked to be given a medical checkup and that he planned to visit his brother in coming days.</p>
<p>In July, Binh was transferred without notice to his family from his prison in his home province Nghe An to another facility in Quang Nam province some 500 km (300 miles) away.</p>
<p>Binh, a blogger on environmental issues, had also served as vice president of the independent Viet Labour Movement and is a member of a soccer group that protests China’s territorial claims on the South China Sea.</p>
<p>He was handed a 14-year prison term in February for “abusing democratic freedoms” and “obstructing officials in the performance of their duties” under Articles 257 and 258 of Vietnam’s penal code.</p>
<p>Binh was arrested on May 15, 2017, by police officers who dragged him from his car more than a year after protests over the government’s response to a waste spill the year before by a Taiwan-owned Formosa Plastics Group steel plant.</p>
<p>The spill killed an estimated 115 tons of fish and left fishermen jobless in four coastal provinces.<b><i><br /> <br /> Reported by RFA's Vietnamese Service. Translated by Viet Ha. Written in English by Paul Eckert.</i></b></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Chinese Warships Visit Cambodia to ‘Strengthen Cooperation’ as Western Influence Wanes</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/cambodia/warships-01092019162023.html</guid>
        <description>Observers say the visit demonstrates financial and military support for Prime Minister Hun Sen’s regime.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 22:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/cambodia/warships-01092019162023.html/cambodia-china-warship-jan-2019-crop.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[One of three Chinese warships anchored at the port of Sihanoukville in southwestern Cambodia, Jan. 9, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ministry of Defense spokesman Chhum Socheat's Facebook page]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Three Chinese warships arrived in southern Cambodia’s coastal city of Sihanoukville Wednesday on a visit the two authoritarian governments said will promote stronger bilateral ties, a warming that comes as Western influence wanes in the Southeast Asian nation following an election last year seen as unfree and unfair.<br /><br />The ships carrying some 700 crew members will stay in port for four days, during which Xu Haihan, a delegate from the Chinese navy, will meet with Defense Minister Tea Banh and other Cambodian military officials, Ministry of Defense spokesman Chhum Socheat said in a statement posted to his Facebook page.<br /><br />“The Chinese warship visit will strengthen friendship and cooperation between the Cambodian and Chinese military,” the statement said, noting that Chinese naval vessels have visited Cambodia 17 times in recent years.<br /><br />China and Cambodia have recently held joint military exercises and Beijing has pledged to help fund a modernization of the Southeast Asian nation’s military.<br /><br />Meanwhile, China has been pouring investment into Cambodia in recent years, causing some Cambodians to question what type of influence Beijing might have over their government.<br /><br />The arrival of the Chinese warships comes amid speculation that Beijing is building a 45,000 hectare (111,200-acre) naval base in Cambodia’s Koh Kong province, based on a Nov. 15 report by Hong Kong’s Asia Times online news portal, which cited unnamed diplomatic sources.<br /><br />Cambodia’s Prime Minister Hun Sen later dismissed the report, saying such a move would violate the constitution, while Cambodia’s Ministry of National Defense called it “fake news” and part of a “foreign campaign to mislead the public and the international community with the intention of destroying the country’s independence and neutrality.”<br /><br />If such a naval base were built on the Gulf of Thailand, it would allow China to significantly expand patrols on the South China Sea, which Beijing claims much of, while rival Taiwan and ASEAN countries Brunei, Malaysia, the Philippines and Vietnam have their own stakes in the waters.<br /><br />Cambodia has increasingly backed China in disputes with the ASEAN nations over its actions in the sea.<br /><br />Meanwhile, Western influence in Cambodia is on the decline amid criticism of Hun Sen and his ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) over rollbacks on democracy in the lead up to and aftermath of a July 29 election in which the CPP effectively ran uncontested and won all 125 seats after a ban of the opposition party.<br /><br />The CPP overwhelmingly won the election following the Supreme Court’s November 2017 dissolution of the main opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP) and a five-year ban on the political activities of 118 of its senior officials for the party’s role in an alleged plot to topple the government.<br /><br />The U.S. has since announced visa bans on individuals seen as limiting democracy in the country, as part of a series of measures aimed at pressuring Cambodia to reverse course, and the European Union, which was the second biggest trade partner of Cambodia in 2017, has said it will drop a preferential trade scheme for Cambodian exports based on the country’s election environment.<br /><br /><b>‘Show of strength’</b><br /><br />Political Analyst Kim Sok told RFA’s Khmer Service on Wednesday that China’s visit is meant not only to “strengthen friendship and cooperation” between the two nations, but to demonstrate support of Hun Sen’s regime both financially and militarily.<br /><br />“The Chinese warship is here as a show of strength against foreign sanctions,” he said, noting that Cambodia hasn’t shown any signs of backing down in the face of Western pressure.<br /><br />But he warned that as Hun Sen faces a political deadlock and home and increasingly pushes the West away, “he has no choice but to rely on the Chinese.”<br /><br />RFA was unable to reach CPP spokesman Phay Siphan for comment on Wednesday.<br /><br />Hun Sen has repeatedly stressed that his country does not need foreign governments to recognize the legitimacy of Cambodia’s elections, saying acceptance by Cambodians is sufficient.<br /><br />He has also said that he will continue to welcome aid from China, which is poised to overtake the U.S. as the world’s top foreign donor, and which is currently Cambodia’s largest international aid provider.<br /><br />China, which typically offers aid to countries without many of the prerequisites that the U.S. and EU place on donations, such as improvements to human rights and rule of law, offered “sincere congratulations” to Hun Sen’s party for its showing in July’s polls.<br /><br />Trade volume between Cambodia and China was valued at U.S. $5.8 billion in 2017, up 22 percent from U.S. $4.76 billion dollars a year earlier, while China is currently Cambodia’s largest investor, and has poured U.S. $12.6 billion into the Southeast Asian nation from 1994 to 2017. <br /><br /><i><b>Reported by Tin Zakariya for RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Rakhine Political Parties to Meet Over Myanmar Official’s Remarks on Ethnic Army</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/rakhine-political-parties-to-meet-01092019163358.html</guid>
        <description>Prominent Rakhine residents and ordinary citizens in the western state are riled up over statements about the Arakan Army.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 21:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/rakhine-political-parties-to-meet-01092019163358.html/myanmar-border-police-helicopter-buthidaung-twp-jan6-2019.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Myanmar Police Chief Lieutenant General Aung Win Oo and others prepare to board a helicopter in Sittwe, capital of western Myanmar's Rakhine state, to fly to Buthidaung township in the northern part of the state, Jan. 6, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>A Rakhine political party said Wednesday that it will hold a meeting in Rakhine state’s capital Sittwe to discuss a warning by a central government spokesman this week against support for the region’s ethnic military force following a deadly attack it conducted on police outposts.</p>
<p>The Buddhist Arakan National Party (ANP) has invited other Rakhine-based political parties, civil society organizations, and locals to join in the talks, scheduled for Jan. 12, on remarks by President’s Office spokesman Zaw Htay on Monday cautioning backers of the Arakan Army (AA) to no longer support the insurgent organization, said ANP vice chairperson Aye Nu Sein.</p>
<p>Specifically, the ANC has invited the Arakan League for Democracy and ethnic Mro and Daing-net political parties, she said.</p>
<p>Participants will also discuss the return home of thousands of civilians displaced by hostilities between the AA and Myanmar government forces that have intensified since December in the rebel army’s quest for greater autonomy for the Rakhine people, as well as prospects for peace in the troubled state.</p>
<p>The Myanmar government denounced the AA’s coordinated assaults on four police outposts in northern Rakhine last week, which killed 13 policemen and wounded nine others, and vowed to crush the insurgents.</p>
<p>Zaw Htay called the attacks a “stab in the back” by the AA and accused it of having ties to the Arakan Rohingya Salvation Army (ARSA), a shadowy Muslim militant group that in August 2017 launched deadly assaults on police outposts in the same region, triggering a brutal military crackdown that drove more than 725,000 Rohingya across the border to Bangladesh.</p>
<p>The ANP issued a statement on Tuesday, rejecting the comments.</p>
<p>Notable Rakhine figures and ordinary residents also denounced the accusations leveled by Zaw Htay.</p>
<p>Rakhine historian Aye Chan called on the government spokesman to prove the allegation that the AA, which represents the region’s Buddhist Rahkine ethnic group, has ties to ARSA, which purports to speak for Muslim Rohingyas.</p>
<p>“He said something like the AA and ARSA are allies, but he needs to prove it,” he said. “He also warned Rakhine people to stop supporting AA. Whether Rakhine people support AA or not, he shouldn’t say something like this which can be read as a threat to people.”</p>
<p>Because the President’s Office is responsible for what Zaw Htay says publicly, President Win Myint, State Counselor Aung San Suu Kyi, and military chief Min Aung Hlaing should take responsibility for the accusations if they instructed him to make the comments, Aye Chan said.</p>
<p>Muslim leader Thar Aye said Zaw Htay presented no concrete proof that the AA is linked to ARSA.</p>
<p>“He can’t prove anything about the AA having ties to ARSA. … Instead of using his authority to give an order, he should try to see what is really going on, study what the root causes of the problem are, and talk with the relevant parties to find a solution.”</p>
<p><b><div style="width:622px;" class="image-inline captioned">
 <div style="width:622px;">
  <img src="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/rakhine-political-parties-to-meet-01092019163358.html/myanmar-idps-kyauktaw-twp-rakhine-jan4-2019.jpg/image" alt="myanmar-idps-kyauktaw-twp-rakhine-jan4-2019.jpg" title="myanmar-idps-kyauktaw-twp-rakhine-jan4-2019.jpg" height="350" width="622" />
 </div>
 <div class="image-caption">
    <span style="width:622px;">Civilians displaced by violence between ethnic Rakhine rebels and Myanmar's army arrive at a camp in Kyauktaw township, western Myanmar's Rakhine state, Jan. 4, 2019.</span>
    
            <span class="copyright">Credit: AFP</span>
    
    
 </div>
</div>

Difficult circumstances for villagers</b></p>
<p>Local relief groups estimate that the number of civilians displaced by recent armed clashes between the AA and Myanmar forces is now well over 5,000 in all of Rakhine state.</p>
<p>The skirmishes and the Myanmar Army’s restrictions on food supplies have caused an estimated 2,000 villagers from communities across Rakhine’s Kyauktaw township alone to flee to safety to other areas.</p>
<p>Government forces began restricting food supplies in the region on Dec. 28 following clashes with AA troops, one displaced resident told RFA in an earlier report.</p>
<p>“We had to leave everything — homes, farms, cattle and other animals,” said Maung Thwin, a resident of Nga Sarine Gaing village.</p>
<p>“The fighting needs to cease in order for us to return home so that we can make purchases of food supplies,” he said.</p>
<p>But even after they return home, the displaced villagers expect to face hunger and hardship because business owners in the community are afraid to open their shops and military restrictions on food supplies are still in place, he said.</p>
<p>The AA has accused the Myanmar military of using local police and security guards to cut off food supplies from flowing into areas where fighting is underway.</p>
<p>Area residents say Myanmar soldiers based in Kyauktaw’s Taung Min Kalar village are preventing civilians from transporting supplies of staple foods by water.</p>
<p>One villager who declined to be named told RFA that residents from the township’s Thalu Chaung village sought permission to carry a sack of rice for each household from Kan Sauk village after experiencing a food shortage, but the army denied them permission.</p>
<p>Instead, they were allowed to take only one small basket of rice for each household based on the recommendation of local administrative officials and police, he said.</p>
<p>A woman from Thalu Chaung village said families now have to live on porridge.</p>
<p>Displaced villager Maung Aye told RFA that he wants to return to his community because his family had to leave behind all their livestock and personal possessions.</p>
<p>Kyauktaw township lawmaker Maung Than Sein said the current circumstances present a very big problem for local Rakhines.</p>
<p>“The Rakhine region is tough to live in, while education levels are low,” he said. “Most people are daily wage earners as well. Under these circumstances, our lives will become very troublesome if the military operations are not stopped.”</p>
<p>Local authorities say restrictions on food supplies are aimed at cutting off supplies for the Arakan Army.</p>
<p>RFA could not reach Colonel Win Zaw Oo of Myanmar military’s Western Command, which oversees operations in Rakhine state, for comment.</p>
<p><b>Concerns about sickness</b></p>
<p>Aye Kywe Yee, a midwife who is helping displaced villagers, said she and others have been providing basic health care services to everyone, including children, pregnant women, and the elderly.</p>
<p>Aung Kyaw Nyunt, a clerk at the Wataung village administration office expressed concern about displaced villagers becoming ill.</p>
<p>“It’s winter and very cold here,” he said. “Health issues can arise because they have to sleep on the ground on plastic sheets.”</p>
<p>Myanmar political observer Yan Myo Thein said the current crisis in Rakhine highlights the urgent need for stakeholders to find a political solution to the ongoing war.</p>
<p>The Tatmadaw, as the Myanmar military is known, declared a four-month unilateral cease-fire in December in five military regions to try to revive the country's shaky peace process by enticing separatist ethnic armies to join talks with the central government. The cease-fire excludes Rakhine state, however.</p>
<p>“In my view, one of the causes [of the continuing conflict] may be the Tatmadaw’s unilateral cease-fire announcement that fails to cover the entire nation,” Yan Myo Thein said. “The nationwide cease-fire is much more important to achieve sustainable peace in the country.”</p>
<p>The escalating hostilities prompted Knut Ostby, the United Nations chief in Myanmar, on Tuesday to express shock over reports of the Jan. 4 attacks by the AA and the loss of lives.</p>
<p>“The resident and humanitarian coordinator urges all sides to ensure the protection of all civilians and uphold their responsibilities under international humanitarian and human rights law,” said a statement issued by the U.N.</p>
<p>Ostby appealed to all sides to step up efforts to find a peaceful solution to the crisis and ensure humanitarian access to all people affected by the violence.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Kyaw Lwin Oo, Kyaw Thu, and Min Thein Aung for RFA’s Myanmar Service. Translated by Khet Mar and Nandar Chann. Written in English by Roseanne Gerin.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Report: Illegal Logging Still Rampant in Cambodia’s Prey Lang Forest</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/cambodia/illegal-logging-cambodia-01092019153808.html</guid>
        <description>Grassroots environmental group criticizes government efforts to stop tree poachers.</description>
        
	        <author>By Eugene Whong</author>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/cambodia/cambodia-rosewood-06242016130935.html/cambodia-logging-06242016.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Trucks loaded with timber wait at Cambodian Bavet border post with Vietnam, in file photo. ]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Deforestation in Prey Lang forest in the central plains of Cambodia continues to be a major problem that threatens the local economy, food security and biodiversity, and has the potential to accelerate climate change, according to a recent report by the Prey Lang Community Network (PLCN).</p>
<p>The local grassroots movement to preserve the forest found that the major culprit in deforestation is illegal logging, which has increased in recent years. The group’s 7<sup>th</sup> Monitoring Report, published Monday, also says that the government is making the situation worse by requiring permits to patrol the forest. In addition, roads are causing habitat loss within the forest.</p>
<p>“Illegal logging is still happening at an alarming rate,” the report says.</p>
<p>“Satellite imagery showed a forest loss of 5,600 ha in 2017. This is equivalent to twenty-one football fields of forest disappearing every day.”</p>
<p>Hoeun Sopheap, a Prey Lang activist based in Kampong Thom province, told RFA’s Khmer Service that within the past year, while patrolling the forest, he observed that illegal logging is still rampant and that the loggers have built roads that help them to evade the law. The government is actually making it harder to stamp out illegal logging.</p>
<p>“If we patrol the forest without the cooperation of the Ministry of Environment, they consider it as illegal activity,” He said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, activists from the PLCN criticize the Ministry for failing to resolve a petition they sent regarding a land concession that granted more than 30,000 hectares in Kratie and Stung Treng provinces to Ci Biotech Co ltd.</p>
<p>They asked the Ministry to clarify terms of the concession because it affects protected forest and wildlife sanctuaries.</p>
<p>The activists petitioned the ministry in 2015 and 2016 after the government granted concession to Ci Biotech in 2012 to replant trees on degraded forest areas but there has been no response.</p>
<p>The activists say they have seen saw mill depots in the area and have witnessed loggers exporting timber using the company’s name.</p>
<p>Activist Yim Sopheak said by law, the government can’t grant concessions of more than 10,000 hectares of land, about a third of the concession this particular company received.</p>
<p>Another activist, Ek Vanna, said the company’s activities haven’t benefited the surrounding villages.</p>
<p>“The company doesn’t develop anything, they just cut down the wood,” he said. He added that the company also hasn’t planted any trees.</p>
<p>RFA attempted to contact Ministry Spokesman Neth Pheaktra for comment on Tuesday but were unable to reach him.</p>
<p>The report recommends removing restrictions on independent patrolling, the closure of logging roads and stopping construction on new roads in the forest, unless absolutely necessary.</p>
<p>PLCN was unsparing in its dim view of government efforts to prevent illegal logging in the report.</p>
<p>“It seems there are no specific measures being taken to address these violations,” the Network wrote.</p>
<p>“Remarkably, every day, many tractors loaded with timber pass unencumbered through forest ranger checkpoints. The timber is not being confiscated and the offenders face no legal consequences for their crimes,” they wrote.</p>
<p>Cambodia has long endured the rampant smuggling of logs and timber—often with the complicity of local authorities—to neighbors such as China and Vietnam, where the wood is used to make high-end furniture.</p>
<p>In May last year, a report by the U.K.-based Environmental Investigation Agency (EIA) said that around 300,000 cubic meters (10,594,400 cubic feet) of timber—including endangered rosewood—had been smuggled out of protected areas in Cambodia to Vietnam with the help of local authorities through some U.S. $13 million paid in bribes between November 2016 and March 2017.</p>
<p>According to the NASA Earth Observatory website, between 2001 and 2014 Cambodia lost a total of 1.44 million hectares (5,560 square miles) of forest—one of the world’s fastest rates of deforestation.</p>
<p><strong><i>Additional reporting by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun.</i></strong></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Abandons Further Democratic Reform as China Tightens Grip</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/reform-01092019124611.html</guid>
        <description>Officials move ahead with plans to criminalize any 'insult' to China's national anthem, without specifying which situations could result in prosecution.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 19:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/reform-01092019124611.html/china-nip2-010919.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Hong Kong official Patrick Nip addresses a press conference in Hong Kong, Jan. 9, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>The Hong Kong government on Wednesday ruled out any further attempt at democratic reform as the government moves ahead with plans to criminalize 'insults' to the national anthem of the People's Republic of China.<br /><br />Patrick Nip, the city's top official in charge of constitutional affairs and liaison with the ruling Chinese Communist Party government in Beijing, said Hong Kong is "in no position" to restart democratic reforms, saying that doing so could be "rash" and lead to "extreme action."<br /><br />Nip, who was responding to a question from pro-democracy lawmaker James To about the likelihood of a democratically elected chief executive for the city in 2022, didn't specify what he meant by "extreme action."<br /><br />He said an Aug. 31, 2014 decree by China's parliament insisting that election candidates be screened by Beijing was a fundamental condition for any reform.<br /><br />"If we are to restart constitutional reform, or further promote its development, this is a starting point," Nip said of the National People's Congress standing committee legal interpretation that sparked the 79-day 2014 Occupy Central civil disobedience movement for fully democratic elections.<br /><br />"If we cannot even reach a consensus on this fundamental legal basis, I don't see how we are in a position to further our reform proposal," he said.<br /><br />His comments came as Hong Kong fell to 73rd place in the Economic Intelligence Unit's (EIU's) annual global democracy index.<br /><br />Last year's banning of the pro-independence Hong Kong National Party (HKNP) and the political screening of election candidates had weakened the city's "already weak democracy," the EIU said.<br /><br /><b>Draft law still vague</b><br /><br />Meanwhile, Nip said the government is going ahead with laws that will ban any act of "altering or insulting" the national anthem, with criminal penalties of up to three years' imprisonment.<br /><br />Police will be given the freedom to bring charges against suspects for up to two years after the alleged offense, Nip said. The usual time limit is six months for minor offenses under Hong Kong law.<br /><br />A draft copy of the bill previously indicated that anyone present in a public place when the "March of the Volunteers" is being played is required to "stand up and show respect."<br /><br />Civic Party lawmaker Jeremy Tam said the current draft is too vague about what exactly constitutes an "insult" to the national anthem.<br /><br />"Let us not forget that this legislation is being proposed by the government," Tam said. "They have a duty to explain the various situations in which such acts might take place, and which acts would and would not be in breach of this law."<br /><br />"And yet, at today's press conference, they refused to give a straight answer to questions about different situations," he said. "The government can't seem to tell us, and yet they want to legislate."<br /><br />Use of the rousing revolutionary tune, which marks the struggle of the ruling Chinese Communist Party to found the People's Republic, will also likely be banned in advertising, at private funerals, or as background music in public venues.<br /><br /><b>National anthem jeered at match</b><br /><br />The move came after Hong Kong football fans jeered, turned their backs, and yelled Cantonese obscenities as the national anthem was played over the loudspeakers at the start of recent soccer matches in the city.<br /><br />Meanwhile, the last British colonial governor of Hong Kong, Chris Patten, said the city had undergone a "general tightening of control" since President Xi Jinping took power in late 2012.<br /><br />"There was a general tightening of control,” Patten told a parliamentary foreign affairs committee in Westminster on Tuesday.<br /><br />"[Hong Kong's autonomy] isn’t just about capitalism, it’s about the rule of law. It’s about free speech, it’s about all the freedoms we associate with pluralism, and I think that’s happened to a considerable extent over the past half a dozen years," he said.<br /><br /><i><b>Reported by Lee Wang-yam for RFA's Cantonese Service, and by Hwang Chun-mei for the Mandarin Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>More Than 80 Percent of Taiwanese Reject China's 'Unification' Plan</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/more-than-80-percent-of-taiwanese-01092019115150.html</guid>
        <description>President Tsai Ing-wen's insistence that Beijing respect the island's democracy and statehood also wins widespread favor.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/more-than-80-percent-of-taiwanese-01092019115150.html/china-tsai-ing-wen-taiwan-jan5-2019.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Taiwan's President Tsai Ing-wen speaks during a press conference at the Presidential Palace in Taipei, Jan. 5, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p><b>UPDATED at 2:02 P.M. EST on 2018-01-09</b></p>
<p>More than 80 percent of Taiwanese would reject unification with mainland China under the Chinese Communist Party's proposed "one country, two systems" model already in place in Hong Kong and Macau, according to a recent opinion poll.</p>
<p>The results came after Taiwan president Tsai Ing-wen rejected calls from Chinese President Xi Jinping for the democratic island to "unify" with the People's Republic, saying its people have no wish to give up their sovereignty.</p>
<p>In the poll of 1,074 Taiwan residents, more than 61 percent of respondents expressed satisfaction with Tsai's response to Xi, while more than 80 percent said they disapproved of the notion of "one country, two systems" according to Beijing's formulation.</p>
<p>More than 85 percent of respondents supported Tsai's four key conditions for any talks to begin with Beijing: namely, that the People's Republic of China hold formal, state-to-state talks with Taiwan while recognizing its status as a sovereign nation, the Republic of China that fled to the island in 1949 after losing a civil war to the communists on the mainland.</p>
<p>In addition, China would have to "respect Taiwan’s freedom and democracy, deals with the country on peaceful and equal terms, and communicate only on a government-to-government basis," Tsai said.</p>
<p>She said Taiwan "utterly rejects" the idea of "one country, two systems."</p>
<p>Beijing is highly unlikely to agree to such conditions, as it regards the island as a renegade province awaiting "unification," although the Chinese Communist Party has never ruled Taiwan.</p>
<p>The survey by Taiwan's Cross-Straits Policy Association was intended to measure public response to recent statements by Tsai and Xi.</p>
<p>In a Jan. 2 "Letter to our Taiwan compatriots," Xi was insistent that China must be "unified."</p>
<p>"It has been a historical and unavoidable duty of the Chinese Communist Party, Chinese government, and the Chinese people to resolve the matter of Taiwan and unify the motherland ever since 1949," Xi said in the statement.</p>
<p>But he made scant reference to public opinion among the 23 million inhabitants of Taiwan, and said that China would make no promises not to use military force.</p>
<p><b>Veiled threat</b></p>
<p>Many in the region have viewed Xi's "no promises" comment as a veiled threat to Taiwan, and the notion of "one country, two systems" has found little favor even among the opposition nationalist Kuomintang (KMT), which has traditionally sought to improve relations with Beijing.</p>
<p>KMT lawmaker Chiang Wan-an on Tuesday said he was against Xi's proposal for the island, and that he supported Tsai's conditions, known as the "four musts."</p>
<p>“Taiwan is not Hong Kong,” he said, adding that most Taiwanese would not accept unification under the formula.</p>
<p>The "one country, two systems" model was promised to Hong Kong after its 1997 handover to China as an alternative to the direct imposition of Communist Party rule.</p>
<p>However, that city's autonomy has been eroded in recent years by a series of high-profile interventions from Beijing, according to U.S. and U.K. officials, Hong Kong's Bar Association, and international rights groups.</p>
<p>According to Fan Shih-ping of National Taiwan Normal University, Washington is unlikely to want to see Taiwan assimilated into China, either.</p>
<p>"If Taiwan did wind up as part of one country, two systems, that would leave a big hole in U.S. ... strategy for surrounding and containing China in the Pacific," Fan said.</p>
<p>"The U.S. probably sees Tsai Ing-wen and the [ruling] Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) as the most likely to resist this," he said.</p>
<p>Fan added that saber-rattling by Beijing has typically always boosted the DPP, come the next election.</p>
<p>Wang Chih-sheng, secretary-general of the pro-DPP Cross-Strait Policy Association, said the DPP is right to try to build a consensus in Taiwan.</p>
<p>"If the DPP continues with its Taiwan consensus policy ... including cross-party support, the youth and the elderly, then they will be able to build a policy platform that the majority of citizens buy into," Wang said.</p>
<p>"It doesn't matter what they call it; but ... we could make a new consensus to use when Beijing tries to ... force the situation," he said.</p>
<p><b>‘A sacred land’</b></p>
<p>Meanwhile, Taiwan's indigenous people said they have been on the island for 6,000 years, and have no wish to be assimilated into a Chinese nation and treated as "ethnic minorities."</p>
<p>"Taiwan is a sacred land where generations of our ancestors lived, and protected it with their lives," they said in an open letter to President Xi. "It has never belonged to China."</p>
<p>"We have fought against imperialism and every foreign intruder of our land. We have suffered military suppression from colonial and authoritarian regimes," it said. "We have never given up our rightful claim to the sovereignty of Taiwan."</p>
<p>"No government, political party, or organization has the right to negotiate with any foreign power in an attempt to surrender the control of the traditional territory of ours, the indigenous peoples of Taiwan," the letter said.</p>
<p>Tseng Hwa-teh, a member of the Paiwan community, said his people were in favor of self-governance and self-determination.</p>
<p>"It is the fundamental and only idea that will allow different ethnic groups to live in happiness and mutual appreciation and respect on the earth," Tseng said. "It's no longer in keeping with the spirit of the times for us to swallow past oppression."</p>
<p>Officially, Taiwan is still known as the Republic of China, which controls the four islands of Taiwan, Penghu, Kinmen and Matsu.</p>
<p>But Beijing has refused diplomatic ties with any country that also recognizes the Republic of China, and actively encourages Taiwan's partners to switch recognition.</p>
<p>Taiwan was ruled as a Japanese colony in the 50 years prior to the end of World War II, but was handed back to the 1911 Republic of China under the KMT government as part of Tokyo's post-war reparation deal.</p>
<p>The island began a transition to democracy following the death of Chiang's son, President Chiang Ching-kuo, in January 1988, starting with direct elections to the legislature in the early 1990s and culminating in the first direct election of a president, Lee Teng-hui, in 1996.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Hwang Chun-mei for RFA's Mandarin Service, and by Chung Kuang-cheng and Pan Jiaqing for the Cantonese Service. Translated and edited by Luisetta Mudie.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Experts: Kim Jong Un’s Visit to China Sends Dual Message to US</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/korea/kim-visits-china-january-2019-01082019175759.html</guid>
        <description>Second Kim-Trump summit likely, but Kim intends to play ‘China card.’</description>
        
	        <author>By Eugene Whong</author>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/korea/kim-visits-china-january-2019-01082019175759.html/kim-china-2019-jan.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[kim-china-2019-jan]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Kim Jong Un’s fourth visit to China is an indication that North Korea’s leader is preparing for another summit with President Donald Trump, but this week’s visit is also meant to send the message that China and North Korea have strategic ties that Washington cannot ignore, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>According to the state-run Korean Central News Agency (KCNA), Kim’s sojourn in China is to last from Jan. 7-10 and will center on meetings with China’s President Xi Jinping, likely to discuss strategy ahead of negotiations with the United States.</p>
<p>Kim’s first diplomatic foray of 2019, followed a hectic year of Korean peninsula diplomacy last year, with Kim also meeting South Korean President Moon Jae-in three times and holding a high-profile Singapore summit with Trump in June.</p>
<p>Key points expected to be discussed at a proposed second North Korea-U.S. summit are North Korea’s denuclearization, addressed in Singapore in a vaguely worded pledge.</p>
<p>With progress on nuclear issues stalled, Kim has started to demand relief from sanctions implemented under U.N. Security Council resolutions in response to Pyongyang’s repeated nuclear and ballistic missile tests over the past decade.</p>
<p>Experts say that this visit also underscores that China has a major role to play in U.S. negotiations with North Korea and that Chinese involvement in North Korean issues could be used by Beijing as a bargaining chip in tense trade negotiations between the U.S. and China.</p>
<p>“This is another example of Kim Jong Un taking advantage of the situation in Washington and going to China not only to get permission from Xi Jinping but to send an underlying message to Washington, to Trump being that hey, you’re not the only game in town. I have this big China card. So I think there is a dual message there,” said Joseph Yun, Senior Adviser to the Asia Program at the US Institute for Peace.</p>
<p>“Essentially this is pretty much the repeat of last year, when he went to China to get the green light from Xi Jinping that it is okay to have another summit, with Trump,” said Yun, a retired U.S. diplomat who was speaking on a panel in Washington on Northeast Asia strategy in 2019.</p>
<p>“I do think that a second summit will be arranged quite soon, probably at the end of February or early March,” he added.</p>
<p>Former U.S. ambassador to South Korea Kathleen Stephens told the same panel that the Kim-Xi meeting showed the importance of the U.S. working closely with other governments in dealing with North Korean issues.</p>
<p>“We need to deepen the process of consultations with Seoul and also with others in the region,” said Stephens, president and CEO of the Washington-based Korea Economic Institute of America.</p>
<p>“Kim Jong Un going to China is a reminder, and probably a very explicit one, that China has both equity and influence in this,” she said.</p>
<p>Former Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Christopher Hill told RFA’s Korean Service that this week’s meetings in Beijing are “part of the process of warming between North Korea and China.”</p>
<p>“China is not happy with the way the U.S. has pursued [the nuclear] issue. The U.S. has gone on the bilateral track and ignored other players in the region, especially China,” said Hill.</p>
<p>Hill expressed concern that the Chinese may be pressing on Kim their view that the U.S. should remove its 28,000 troops from South Korea as part of any settlement and they may attempt to encourage him to stick to that point in negotiations with Trump.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Bruce Bennett, a researcher for the RAND Corporation, said of the meeting, “Kim has been clearly preparing for his second summit meeting with President Trump.”</p>
<p>“I think that Kim is worried that the President will tell him ‘enough is enough’. It’s time for Kim to stop stalling on denuclearization,” he said.</p>
<p>“Kim wants China’s support. Kim also wants China to relax economic sanctions against North Korea, because China is North Korea’s major trading partner. Any action it takes to relax sanctions could make a major difference for North Korea,” said Bennett.</p>
<p><b>Across the pond</b></p>
<p>Experts in South Korea seemed to agree with the assessments of their U.S. counterparts.</p>
<p>Professor Shin Sangjin of Kwangwoon University said, “Kim’s visit to China indicates that another U.S.-North Korea summit will happen soon, especially since President Trump has been saying possible locations are being discussed.”</p>
<p>“Kim wants to maximize his leverage in negotiations with the U.S. Also I think that North Korea is aiming to deliver a clear message that China strongly remains its cooperative ally in the region,” said Shin.</p>
<p>Cho Han-Bum of the Korea Institute for National Unification said that the visit is in line with themes discussed by Kim during his New Year’s address, in which he warned that Pyongyang may change its approach to nuclear talks if Washington persists with sanctions.</p>
<p>“[He] indicated multilateral agreements should be pursued to build a permanent peace regime, clearly implying the role of China,” Cho said.</p>
<p>“North Korea is [through the visit] boasting its improved ties with China.”</p>
<p><strong><i>Additional Reporting by Sangmin Lee and Yong Jae Mok for RFA’s Korean Service. Translated by Yewon Ji.</i></strong></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Myanmar Holds Talks With China to Reopen Border Crossing in Northern Shan State</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmar-holds-talks-with-china-to-reopen-border-crossing-01082019165648.html</guid>
        <description>Fruit dealers rely on the Muse-Ruili passage to export their produce to China’s Yunnan province.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/chinese-authorities-arrest-myanmar-nationals-11282018165055.html/myanmar-border-crossing-china-undatd-photo.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Vehicles and motorbikes line up in Myanmar to pass through a border crossing to China in an undated photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[RFA]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>Myanmar’s deputy commerce minister met China’s ambassador to the country on Monday in Naypyidaw to discuss the reopening of the busy border crossing at Muse in northern Shan state for trucks carrying Myanmar produce and seafood, whose closure in December caused hardship for traders.</p>
<p>Deputy Commerce Minister Aung Htoo and a delegation from the Chinese embassy on Monday agreed to extend operating hours at the alternative Kyukok-Pansai border crossing and to add two additional lanes there to let trucks pass while the Kyin San Kyawt passage north of Muse township remains closed.</p>
<p>Minister of Commerce Than Myint, who also attended the meeting, said officially designating Kyin San Kyawt as a regular border gate would relieve traffic congestion between the countries during the watermelon and muskmelon season, Myanmar News Agency reported.</p>
<p>The Kyin San Kyawt crossing is used only to transport fruit and seafood export from Myanmar into China.</p>
<p>When Myanmar soldiers first shut down the crossing on Dec. 27 but gave no reason for the closure, more than 1,000 Myanmar trucks carrying mainly watermelon to China eventually became stranded, causing huge financial losses for farmers and fruit dealers, those involved in the business said.</p>
<p>But some dealers blamed the border closure on Chinese authorities responsible for inspecting the contents of the vehicles, citing a lack of manpower, though it later came to light that their use of advanced security measures such as fingerprinting and facial recognition had caused delays.</p>
<p>It was later disclosed that Myanmar shut down the Kyin San Kyawt checkpoint on its side of the border as a security measure after an armed group attacked a local people’s militia, the official <i>Global New Light of Myanmar</i> reported.</p>
<p>As a result, trucks had to be redirected to the Kyukok-Pansai border crossing — an unofficial passage — where they were allowed to enter the Chinese border town of Wanding in Yunnan province’s Ruili city on Dec. 29, the report said.</p>
<p>During the meeting, Li Xiaoyan, minister counselor from the China embassy to Myanmar, discussed efforts to officially open the Kyin San Kyawt border crossing and plan to decrease traffic congestion by increasing cargo inspection times and assigning more inspectors, Myanmar News Agency reported.</p>
<p>The Chinese side also said it would work with Myanmar to increase the number of border passages between the two countries and to quickly reopen the Kyin San Kyawt crossing gate, the report said.</p>
<p>Naing Win, chairman of the Myanmar Watermelon and Muskmelon Producers and Exporters Association, told RFA’s Myanmar Service that Myanmar’s Ministry of Commerce informed his organization that both sides agreed to increase hours at the Kyukok-Pansai border crossing and add two more lanes at the checkpoint.</p>
<p>RFA called the Yan Naing Htun, the ministry’s permanent secretary, for comment, but was unable to reach him.</p>
<p>Fruit traders meanwhile say more than 1,000 trucks have spent hours lined up in the rain to pass through the Kyukok-Pansai crossing which has only two lanes for people and goods passing in both directions between 6 a.m. and 8:30 p.m.</p>
<p>Only 250 trucks can enter China through the crossing each day, they said.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Thiri Min Zin for RFA’s Myanmar Service. Translated by Khet Mar. Written in English by Roseanne Gerin.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Myanmar’s Arakan Army Denies Link to Muslim Militant Group in Rakhine State</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmars-arakan-army-denies-link-01082019163459.html</guid>
        <description>The ethnic army also objects to a government spokesman’s warning for supporters not to back the organization. </description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/myanmar/myanmars-arakan-army-denies-link-01082019163459.html/myanmar-wounded-police-aa-atack-rakhine-jan7-2019.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Lieutenant General Aung Win Oo (2nd R), chief of the Myanmar Police Force, visits an injured border policeman in a hospital in 
Buthidaung township, western Myanmar's Rakhine state, Jan. 7, 2019. ]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AFP]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>The Arakan Army on Tuesday denied that it is allied with a Rohingya Muslim militant group and objected to a Myanmar government spokesman’s warning to its supporters not to back the insurgent organization after it conducted deadly attacks on police outposts in northern Rakhine state last week.</p>
<p>Coordinated assaults by the AA on four police outposts in Buthidaung township on Jan. 4 left 13 policemen dead and injured nine others. The rebel army said it lost three of its soldiers in the violence.</p>
<p>At a news conference on Monday, President’s Office spokesman Zaw Htay accused the AA of having ties to the Arakan Rohingya Salvation Army (ARSA), a Muslim militant group that in August 2017 launched deadly assaults on 30 police outposts and an army base in northern Rakhine state, triggering a brutal military crackdown during which thousands were killed and more than 725,000 Rohingya fled across the border to Bangladesh.</p>
<p>In a statement on its website and Facebook page, the AA said Zaw Htay’s statements were inappropriate, viewing them as an attempt by the government and the military to stir up misunderstanding between the Arakan military group’s allies and ethnic Rakhine support base.</p>
<p>AA commander-in-chief Major General Tun Myat Naing also posted an online message that the AA does not have any connection to ARSA.</p>
<p>The AA, which is fighting the Myanmar military for greater autonomy in Rakhine state, represents the region’s Buddhist Rahkine ethnic group, while ARSA is a militant group that purports to speak for Muslim Rohingyas.</p>
<p>Rakhine ethnics said that it is impossible not to support the AA when all groups in the multiethnic but divided state want equality and the right to self-determination through military and politics means.</p>
<p>They also noted that Rakhine has been the poorest state in Myanmar long before AA attacked the police outposts, thereby negating Zaw Htay’s statement that the region’s development would suffer because of the Rakhine people’s backing of the AA.</p>
<p>Pe Than, a lower house lawmaker from the hard-line Buddhist Arakan National Party (ANP) who represents the Myebon township constituency, said that the Rakhine people did not believe Zaw Htay’s remark that the AA has links to ARSA.</p>
<p>“No Rakhine would accept the AA having ties to the Arakan Rohingya Salvation Army, and it would never happen,” he said.</p>
<p>“If the AA tried to have ties with ARSA, only the AA would face negative consequences,” he said. “We don’t believe these rumors. We want both sides [the government and the AA] to move forward to achieve peace instead of blaming each other.”</p>
<p><b>‘A better way’</b></p>
<p>The AA is one of 11 ethnic armed groups that have not signed the government’s nationwide cease-fire accord of October 2015, an agreement inked by 10 other rebel armies to end decades of civil war in the developing country.</p>
<p>Fighting intensified between the AA and Myanmar Army in December after Arakan troops ambushed a military column conducting “area clearance operations” near the Myanmar-Bangladesh border on Monday, according to an account by the national forces. But the AA attributed the hostilities to an intrusion by the Myanmar military into an AA-controlled area to conduct operations.</p>
<p>Myanmar forces declared a four-month unilateral cease-fire on Dec. 21 in five military regions in a bid to breathe life into the country's teetering peace process by enticing separatist ethnic armies to join talks with the central government. The cease-fire excludes Rakhine state, however.</p>
<p>Ann Thar Gyi, chairman of the local civil society organization Thingaha Kanlat Rakhita Aid Association, said his group will support any organization or individuals if they work for development in Rakhine state.</p>
<p>“The government is talking about development in Rakhine only after having all this fighting in Rakhine,” he said. “It’s like they are saying just what they want to say without thinking about people’s interests.”</p>
<p>Hla Myint, spokesman for the Arakan League for Democracy (ALD), another political party active in Rakhine state, said Zaw Htay’s comments at the press conference would drive people away from the government.</p>
<p>“I believe it would be better to find a better way to resolve the problem,” he said. “Local people in the rural areas have been afraid of both the military as well as of the AA all their lives.”</p>
<p>Kyaukphyu resident Tun Kyi told RFA’s Myanmar Service that he was disappointed with Zaw Htay’s words.</p>
<p>“We have not only the AA as an armed group, but also all other ethnic minorities have their armed groups in the country, and they have been fighting with government army,” he said.</p>
<p>“No ethnic minority will listen to government telling them not to support their armed groups,” he said. “People in Kachin state support the KIA [Kachin Independence Army], and people in Rakhine will support the Rakhine armed group, the AA.”</p>
<p><b>Visit by journalists</b></p>
<p>Meanwhile, a group of journalists on a government-sponsored trip to northern Rakhine on Monday talked to villagers and police officers about the deadly attacks by the AA.</p>
<p>Reporters from RFA, Voice of America, Democratic Voice of Burma, Mizzima and the <i>Myanmar Times </i>arrived in Maungdaw township, adjacent to Buthidaung, by military helicopter along with Lieutenant General Aung Win Oo, chief of the Myanmar Police Force, and Khin Maung Tin, deputy minister of the State Counselor’s Office.</p>
<p>A policeman from the Kahtee Hla police outpost, one of the four stations the AA attacked, told them that their barking dogs alerted police to the approaching insurgents.</p>
<p>“They opened fire with heavy weapons, and we responded with heavy weapons,” he said. “We were engaged in defense for three hours because they had more troops and better weapons. We were very afraid because we never experienced anything like this before.”</p>
<p>Police Sergeant Win Ko from the Kahtee Hla outpost said that some Rakhine villagers were seen with the AA troops during the attack.</p>
<p>“We serve here to protect the Rakhine people, but they helped the AA attack us,” he said, adding that villagers were definitely involved in assaults on the police outpost.</p>
<p>Police Brigadier General Myint Toe, commander of the Border Guard Police Force No. 1, told the reporters that police are now working with the military on ensuring stability in the restive region.</p>
<p><i><b>Reported by Wai Mar Tun and Min Thein Aung for RFA’s Myanmar Service. Translated by Khet Mar. Written in English by Roseanne Gerin.</b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Two Cambodia Opposition Officials Barred From Politics to Seek ‘Pardon’ After Amendment Approval</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/cambodia/pardons-01082019154551.html</guid>
        <description>Acting opposition leader Sam Rainsy urges those banned to refrain from falling into a ruling party ‘trap.’</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 20:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/cambodia/pardons-01082019154551.html/cambodia-hun-sen-parade-jan-2019.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Prime Minister Hun Sen (L) waves to government civil servants with National Assembly President Heng Samrin during a parade at the Olympic Stadium in Phnom Penh, Jan. 7, 2019.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP Photo]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p><b>UPDATED at 1:25 P.M. EST on 2019-01-09</b><br /><br />At least two senior officials from Cambodia’s opposition who were barred from politics said they will seek a “pardon” to have their rights reinstated after King Norodom Sihamoni approved an amendment to the country’s law on political parties on Tuesday.<br /><br />Kong Koam, the former president of the opposition Sam Rainsy Party (SRP), and his son Kong Bora, a former senior official with the main opposition Cambodia National Rescue Party (CNRP), said they will ask for individual “pardons” on Wednesday to resume political activities, according to a condition Prime Minister Hun Sen has said must be met before they can take advantage of the new amendment to overturn their ban.<br /><br />“The reason I will request to be pardoned is because I can’t stay an outlaw,” Kong Bora told RFA’s Khmer Service, adding that he had never violated any law. His father, whose SRP merged with the Human Rights Party (HRP) to form the CNRP ahead of Cambodia’s 2013 ballot, could not be reached for comment.<br /><br />The two were among 118 officials slapped with a five-year suspension of political rights as part of a decision by the Supreme Court in November 2017 to dissolve the CNRP for its role in an alleged plot to topple the government.<br /><br />Prime Minister Hun Sen’s ruling Cambodian People’s Party (CPP) effectively ran uncontested in Cambodia’s July 29 general election and won all 125 seats in parliament, drawing condemnation from Western nations who called the ballot unfree and unfair amid the crackdown on the opposition and other rollbacks on democracy.<br /><br />In late December, Hun Sen’s Constitutional Council unanimously approved an amendment to the draft law on political parties proposed by the one-party parliament, paving the way for the reinstatement of political rights to the 118 CNRP officials, in what was widely seen as a bid to ease international pressure on his government.<br /><br />On Tuesday, the king signed off on the legislation, which does not provide for the reestablishment of the CNRP, and which Hun Sen has said will only allow the opposition officials to return to politics if they each make an individual request for a “pardon.”<br /><br />Critics have called it a “trap” aimed at fracturing the CNRP.<br /><br /><b>Call to ‘remain strong’</b><br /><br />Meanwhile, CNRP acting president Sam Rainsy, who is living in self-imposed exile to avoid a string of convictions issued by courts seen as beholden to Hun Sen, urged the 118 senior CNRP officials to reject the prime minister’s demand that they request pardons, calling it “a trick” in a post to his Facebook page.<br /><br />“I call on the 118 CNRP officials to remain strong, not to fall into Hun Sen's trap, and not to unknowingly serve the current dictatorship,” he wrote.<br /><br />“Please follow the example of [other CNRP members] who have been released from jail and vowed to continue our righteous fight for freedom and democracy.”<br /><br />Sam Rainsy said that the officials should wait until Hun Sen agrees to reinstate the CNRP, release the party’s president Kem Sokha—who is under house arrest facing charges of treason—and call for a new election that includes all parties.<br /><br />CPP spokesman Sok Ey San said Tuesday that with the amendment to the law on political parties approved, his party is waiting for former CNRP officials with open arms.<br /><br />“The door has been opened—all we are waiting for is people to come,” he said.<br /><br />Hun Sen has regularly called on CNRP officials to defect since their party was dissolved and recently suggested that increasing the number of local level government positions in Cambodia would entice formerly elected opposition members to return to politics with the CPP.<br /><br />Last week, parliament approved draft laws to increase the number of positions, but observers have said the current amount is sufficient, and that existing councilors should instead be made more effective through better training and increased budgets.<br /><br /><i><b>Reported by RFA’s Khmer Service. Translated by Samean Yun. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.<br /><br />CORRECTION: An earlier version of this report incorrectly referred to Kong Koam as a former senior CNRP official.<br /></b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>China Jails Three Activists For Video 'Mocking' President Xi Jinping</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/xijinping-insult-01082019134837.html</guid>
        <description>A social media clip made by the activists was judged to have 'insulted' a Chinese leader, leading to 20-month jail terms.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 19:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/china/xijinping-insult-01082019134837.html/activists-insult.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Supporters of Civil Rights and Livelihood Watch website editor Ding Lingjie gather outside a courthouse  in Beijing, Dec. 28, 2018.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[Ren Quanniu]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Authorities in the Chinese capital have sentenced citizen journalist</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Ding Lingjie and two petitioners to jail for making a video 'mocking'</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> President Xi Jinping during a holiday season crackdown on dissent.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Ding was tried alongside petitioners Li Xuehui and Wang Fengxian by</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> the Shijingshan District People's Court in Beijing on Dec. 28, the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Chinese Human Rights Defenders (CHRD) network said in a statement on</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> its website.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">All three were handed 20-month jail terms after being found guilty of</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> "picking quarrels and stirring up trouble," the group, which compiles</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> and translates reports from rights activists inside China, said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Wang's sentence was suspended for two years, and it was unclear if she</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> had any role in the video. However, her elderly mother took part in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> the clip.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">The case against the three hinged on a video clip shot by Li that the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> authorities said had "insulted a national leader" by mocking Xi.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Ding's lawyer Ren Quanniu said his client plans to appeal the jail</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> term, although the vast majority of appeals to higher courts in China</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> result in the upholding of the initial verdict and sentence.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"All three defendants pleaded not guilty ... and also expressed</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> dissatisfaction, as part of their individual defenses, with the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> verdict and sentence," Ren said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">He said there had been a strong police presence outside the court</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> buildings during the sentencing hearing.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"The Beijing authorities dispatched large numbers of police, because</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> there were a lot of people they regard as so-called '[politically]</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> sensitive individuals' being watched," Ren said. "There were a lot of</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> police vehicles and officers outside the court buildings; they took</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> this very seriously."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"Some of [the activists] were taken away from the area around the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> court building by the state security police," he said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><b><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">'<span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Hostile foreign forces'</span></span></b></p>
<p><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "></span>Ding, who is being held at the Shijingshan Detention Center in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Beijing, had been working as an editor of the Civil Rights and</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Livelihood Watch website at the time of her disappearance in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Shandong's Zibo city in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3638_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3644_com_zimbra_date">September 2017</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Police refused to allow her lawyer to meet with her until after she</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> had been formally arrested in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3639_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3645_com_zimbra_date">November 2017</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">, CHRD said.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Liu Feiyue, 48, who founded Civil Rights and Livelihood Watch, stood</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> trial at Hubei's Suizhou Intermediate People's Court in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3640_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3646_com_zimbra_date">August 2018</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">on</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> charges of "incitement to subvert state power."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Xi has repeatedly warned against "hostile foreign forces" attempting</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> to overthrow the ruling Chinese Communist Party by infiltrating China</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> with "Western" religious practices and ideas like democracy,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> constitutional government, and human rights.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Liu was among more than 300 lawyers, law firm staff, rights activists,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> and relatives who were detained, questioned, or placed under</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> surveillance or other restrictions in a nationwide police operation</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> targeting the legal profession and related activists launched in July</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> 2015.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Shandong activist Wang Jiangfeng, who was himself jailed for two years</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> for referring to the president as "Steamed Bun Xi," said the Communist</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Party is terrified of the speed with which video clips can go viral.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"They are really afraid of losing power, because a lot of people in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> China can see all too clearly, and they want democracy," Wang said.</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> "The Chinese Communist Party fears it would lose its power and</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> privilege if that happened."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"That's why they use these methods to suppress people."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Wang was sentenced by the Zhaoyuan People's Court after being found</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> guilty of "picking quarrels and stirring up trouble."</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">He was accused of referring to the head of the ruling Chinese</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> Communist Party as "Steamed Bun Xi" in a group message to the social</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> media platforms WeChat and QQ. His defense attorney Zhu Shengwu was</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> later stripped of his license to practice.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">"Steamed Bun Xi" has been a banned phrase on China's tightly</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> controlled internet since the president ordered the buns during a</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> visit to a Beijing restaurant in</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "><span> </span></span><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3641_com_zimbra_date" style="text-align: start; "><span class="Object" id="OBJ_PREFIX_DWT3647_com_zimbra_date">December 2013</span></span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">, prompting petitioners</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> to gather outside toting a placard that read "President Xi, I'd like</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> to eat steamed buns too" in a bid to get their grievances against the</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> government heard.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">The incident sparked an online meme in which Xi was referred to</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> jokingly as Steamed Bun Xi, in a pun on the name of a legendary Song</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> dynasty official who fought corruption. Censors later banned the meme,</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> deleting social media posts that contained references to it.</span><br style="text-align: start; " /><br style="text-align: start; " /><i><b><span style="text-align: start; float: none; ">Reported by Wong Lok-to for RFA's Cantonese Service. Translated and</span><span style="text-align: start; float: none; "> edited by Luisetta Mudie.</span></b></i></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 
   
    <item>
        <title>Toddler Son of Uyghur Political ‘Re-Education Camp’ Detainees Drowns in Frozen Ditch</title>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/drowning-01082019130159.html</guid>
        <description>Rahmutullah Shirbaqi had been living with his elderly grandparents when he went missing last month.</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 18:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
        

        
            <media:content type="image/png" url="https://www.rfa.org/english/news/uyghur/children-10182017144425.html/uyghur-children-and-police-april-2017-1000.jpg">
              <media:description type="html"><![CDATA[A Uyghur woman carries a toddler as children play near a cage protecting Chinese paramilitary policemen on duty in Urumqi, in a file photo.]]></media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"><![CDATA[AP Photo]]></media:credit>
            </media:content>
        
	    <content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
		    <![CDATA[
            <p>The two-year-old son of an ethnic Uyghur couple detained in a political “re-education camp” in northwest China’s Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region (XUAR) has drowned after falling through ice into an irrigation ditch in Hotan (in Chinese, Hetian) prefecture, according to local officials.<br /><br />Sources recently told RFA’s Uyghur Service that Rahmutullah Shirbaqi disappeared from his home in Qaraqash (Moyu) county’s Zawa township on Dec. 21, while in the care of his grandfather, 78-year-old Matnury Mahsut, and grandmother, 68-year-old Mahtumhan Tursunniyaz.<br /><br />Shirbaqi’s body was found three days later and authorities determined that he had drowned after plunging through ice covering a ditch in front of his house in Chokanjilgha village, where his grandparents had raised him since his parents were sent to the Bostankol Re-education Camp in the county seat a year earlier.<br /><br />An officer at the Hotan prefecture police headquarters told RFA that she was not authorized to discuss Shirbaqi’s case, while two officials from the prefectural government said they had heard a two-year-old boy had died, but were unsure of other details.<br /><br />However, a resident of a neighboring village in Qaraqash told RFA on condition of anonymity that his local ruling Communist Party secretary had recently cautioned villagers to be extra vigilant with their children because of a drowning in the area.<br /><br />“He said we need to take good care of our kids at home because a boy died falling into a ditch,” the resident explained, adding that village officials said the boy’s parents had been detained in a re-education camp, where authorities have detained Uyghurs and other Muslim ethnic minorities accused of harboring “strong religious views” and “politically incorrect” ideas throughout the XUAR since April 2017.<br /><br />While seeking additional information about Shirbaqi’s death, RFA contacted an officer from the Qaraqash county police department, who said the boy has a sister who is a junior at Zawa township’s No. 2 Middle School.<br /><br />“She told the school when her brother disappeared,” the officer said.<br /><br />“Her supervising teacher told me that the boy was found dead. The first thing that came to my mind was, ‘what were the parents doing when he disappeared,’ but then I learned that they weren’t living with him and he was in the care of his grandparents.”<br /><br />The officer said the weather had been quite cold in Hotan in recent weeks and that ice had formed on top of area irrigation ditches around the time Shirbaqi drowned.<br /><br />He said he was unsure whether Shirbaqi’s parents had been sentenced to prison or if they were being held at a re-education camp—only that they “weren’t at home” when the boy went missing.<br /><br />But officials from Chokanjilgha village confirmed Shirbaqi’s parents had been detained at the Bostankol Re-education Camp, with one local police officer saying they were sent to the facility around one year earlier for “a phone issue,” without providing further details.<br /><br />An official from the village government told RFA she had taken Shirbaqi along with his grandparents to the camp multiple times, “but they never got a chance to meet with the boy’s parents.”<br /><br />“The grandparents have pled to meet with the parents, saying their health is poor … but the police guarding the camp won’t let them in,” she said.<br /><br />“We had stamps of approval from the prefectural police department, the county judicial department, the county Public Security Bureau, and the neighborhood committee to visit them. We went to see them 20 times in a two-month period, but were always turned back.”<br /><br />Shirbaqi accompanied his grandparents during their last attempt to visit his parents on Dec. 18, the village official said, just days before he went missing.<br /><br />She said it was unclear whether his parents are aware of his death.<br /><br /><b>Camp network</b><br /><br />While Beijing initially denied the existence of re-education camps, chairman of the XUAR, Shohrat Zakir, told China’s official Xinhua news agency in October that the facilities are an effective tool to protect the country from terrorism and provide vocational training for Uyghurs.<br /><br />Reporting by RFA’s Uyghur Service and other media organizations, however, has shown that those in the camps are detained against their will and subjected to political indoctrination, routinely face rough treatment at the hands of their overseers, and endure poor diets and unhygienic conditions in the often overcrowded facilities.<br /><br />Adrian Zenz, a lecturer in social research methods at the Germany-based European School of Culture and Theology, has said that some 1.1 million people are or have been detained in the camps — equating to 10 to 11 percent of the adult Muslim population of the XUAR.<br /><br />In November 2018, Scott Busby, the deputy assistant secretary in the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights and Labor at the U.S. Department of State, said there are "at least 800,000 and possibly up to a couple of million" Uyghurs and others detained at re-education camps in the XUAR without charges, citing U.S. intelligence assessments.<br /><br />Citing credible reports, U.S. lawmakers Marco Rubio and Chris Smith, who head the bipartisan Congressional-Executive Commission on China, recently called the situation in the XUAR "the largest mass incarceration of a minority population in the world today."<br /><br /><b>Children left behind</b><br /><br />An Oct. 21 report by the official <i>Global Times</i> promoting the camps as “training centers” also included photos of children in Hotan prefecture whose parents had been placed in camps, and claimed that they are warmly cared for at special “schools,” where they engage in educational courses and other activities.<br /><br />But sources have told RFA that Uyghur children whose parents have been sent to camps are regularly sent to orphanages that are seriously overcrowded, calling the conditions “terrible,” with children “locked up like farm animals in a shed.”<br /><br />Others say that while the orphanages received substantial cash donations from the public, “only a very little is spent on the children,” and that the facilities save money by giving the kids meat only once a week, while the rest of the time they are provided with “rice soup.”<br /><br />RFA has received several reports of Uyghur children in the XUAR dying or suffering severe injuries while their parents are detained and they lack adequate care.<br /><br />In August, sources told RFA that a 10-year-old boy from Kashgar (Kashi) prefecture’s Makit (Maigaiti) county, whose parents were being held in a re-education camp, had drowned in the area’s Zerepshan River.<br /><br />In March, sources reported that eight-year-old Esma Ahmet, whose father was being held at a political re-education camp, had suffered burns to nearly 60 percent of her body a month earlier when a stove overturned at her home in Hotan’s Guma (Pishan) county, and was in urgent need of medical treatment.<br /><br /><b><i>Reported by Shohret Hoshur for RFA’s Uyghur Service. Translated by Alim Seytoff. Written in English by Joshua Lipes.</i></b></p>
            
		    ]]>
		</content:encoded>

   </item>
 
 
 </channel>
 
</rss>